见鬼  达西  你真不该来
Oh, shit. Darcy, you really shouldn't have come.
带路
Show me.
北   极
公司态度坚决  要我们继续工作
Corporate was adamant. We keep running.
不许暂停
No stopping operations.
不不不  你得过安检  不许带相机
No, no, no. You got to go through. No cameras.
他居然可以在这杀人  国际法在这可不管用
He's got orders to kill. I don't even think international laws apply up here.
我们首先是地质学家
We are geologists first.
如果这东西有任何重大的历史价值
If this thing has any historical significance at all,
我们就得停工  我会亲自叫停
we are shutting down. I'm shutting us down.
他要朝我开枪吗  那开啊
Oh, he's going to shoot me? Shoot me.
别杀她
Hey, don't kill her.
这太疯狂了
This is crazy stuff.
太疯狂了
Crazy shit.
你怎么看
Well, what do you think?
我觉得历史要被改写了
I think history is about to change.
美国  德州
上报外星人活动
铭记芝加哥
耶格研发中心
我是个脾气不好的女人
I'm a nasty woman
看这是谁来上班了
Oh, look who decided to show up for work.
踩碎一地芳心
I'm a heartbreaker
让你痛哭流涕
Gonna make you cry
怎么  南帕诸岛不适合冲浪吗
What, surf report no good at South Padre?
浪头不够高  车子又没油
The waves are flat and I got no gas.
你懂的  凯德
You know that, Cade.
哥们  真没礼貌
Dude. Rude.
瞧这俩小妞  我的乖乖
Look at these two junebugs. Whoo! My, my!
你会付我这次的工钱吧  凯德
Hey, you're paying me on this one, right, Cade?
拜托你答应给我工资
Please tell me I'm getting paid.
卢卡斯  很多人有工作就知足了
You know, Lucas, a lot of guys are just happy to have a job at all.
或许吧
Yeah, I suppose.
-身上有现金吗  -有
- You got any cash on you? - Yeah.
很好
All right, good.
你好  我是卢卡斯·弗兰纳瑞
Hey, Lucas Flannery.
自1928年以来  这里一直属于我们家
Place has been in the family since '28.
我爷爷花了一辈子经营这里
Granddaddy ran it all his life.
对吧  爷爷
Ain't that right, granddaddy?
他很快就会把这转到我名下
Real soon he's going to sign it over to me.
都是现在的电影害的
The movies nowadays, that's the trouble.
不是续集就是重制  一堆垃圾
Sequels and remakes, bunch of crap.
我真喜欢那一部
I love that one.
他又老又聋
He's deaf and senile.
我听到了
Heard that.
这些只需要稍微整一整
Now these just need some spit and polish.
我想就能放数字电影  没准IMAX都行
I believe they're digital, possibly IMAX.
播放不了的  先生  你不用管我们
Yeah, they're not. Mister, we'll have a look around
我们可以自己看
if you want to leave us to it, okay?
以前人们不远千里来这儿
You know, folks used to come from miles around
看舞女跳恰恰舞
to see the dancing girls with the big cha-chas.
我发誓
I swear to God
他再让我给他换尿布  我就给他下毒
I am one diaper change away from poisoning his oatmeal.
你该坚持来这  老伙计
Hey, you hang in there, buddy.
既然你在这觉得自己更年轻
If coming here makes you feel young,
那就让他天天带你来
then you tell this kid to bring you here every day.
七块卖我  否则我就继续说下去
Seven bucks, I keep talking.
成交
Sold.
还记得小时候这里的样子吗
Remember this place when we were kids?
高中的时候你带几个姑娘来过这里
How many girls you think you brought here in high school?
我只记得一个
I only remember one.
小心头
Hey, heads!
难怪你进不了校队
That's why you didn't make the varsity team.
好  长传
All right. Go long.
算了
Leave it.
迫击炮弹
Mortar shells?
你这是怎么了
What the hell happened to you?
哥们  这卡车多少钱
Hey, snakeballs. How much for the truck?
卡车
Truck?
再两周  姐妹们  就再也不用上课了
Two more weeks, girls, till no more classes, ever.
马上就能晒个古铜色  喝个烂醉了
Almost time to get a tan and get wasted!
邻居们  把东西放在这
钱看着给吧
修理基金
邻居们  把东西放在这
钱看着给吧
拜托  拜托
Please, please.
没有助学金  真是棒极了
No financial aid. Great.
好了  我知道我到家了  谢谢欢迎
Yes, I know I'm home, thank you.
发现入侵者  发现入侵者  严禁私闯民宅
Intruder alert! Intruder alert! Back away from the premises!
-好好识别声音  是我  -我报警了
- Voice recognition. It's me! - I am dialing 911.
随你的便  我无所谓
Go right ahead. I don't care.
我要打电话报警了
I'm still calling 911.
芝加哥一战
The battle of Chicago was an event
永久地改变了我们的世界
that permanently changed our world.
-死亡人数超过一千三  -城市遭到大面积毁灭
- Over 1300 dead. - Much of the city has been destroyed.
国家安全局号召所有人
Homeland security is urging everyone
举报可疑的外星人活动
to report suspicious alien activity.
国会迅速终止了
A swift act of congress put an end to all joint operations
军方和汽车人的所有联合行动  终止了联盟
between the military and the autobots, ending the alliance.
各位委员都知道
As this committee knows,
五年前  芝加哥入侵事件那天
the invasion of Chicago was a defining day
是个决定性的日子
for our nation five years ago.
那一天  无数的人意识到
The day millions of people realized that
我们再也不能让外星人
never again can we allow aliens
为我们而战
to fight our battles for us.
在终止联合作战行动之后
A handful of autobots were given sanctuary
少部分的汽车人获得了安置
after joint-combat operations were abolished.
仅剩十数个霸天虎仍然在逃
Fewer than a dozen Decepticons are still on the run,
这都归功于我们中情局小队
thanks to our CIA unit,
"墓风"队
"Cemetery Wind."
快  把它搬回我家
Hurry, let's get it to my house, guys.
至于外星人的科技
As for the alien technology,
我们的目标是将其掌控在美国手中
our objective remains to keep it in American control.
我叫蒂莫西  这是我的小组成员
Hi. My name is Timothy. This is my crew.
我们在芝加哥发现了这个外星人的球形炮塔
We found this alien ball turret in Chicago.
在碎石堆里发现的  而且还能使用
We just found it in the rubble and it's all working...
有消息说日本  印度
Word has it Japan, India,
以色列可能已经获得若干艘飞船
the Israelis may have gotten their hands on a couple of ships.
据说俄罗斯正准备高价收买
Apparently the Russians are starting a bidding war.
五千块我们就卖
We're taking $5,000 for it.
上面有36把枪  全是外星装备
It's got 36 guns, alien shit.
新时代已然开启
A new era has begun.
变形金刚的时代已经结束了
And the age of the transformers is over.
我一直在等你呢
Hey, I've been waiting for you.
今天你好性感
You're looking hot today!
是吗  那你把衬衣脱了吧
Oh, yeah? How about you taking your shirt off?
你要我现在就脱了吗
You want me to take my shirt off right now?
你爸看到会怎么想  你要去哪
What would your dad think about it? Hey, where you going?
简直不敢相信  太夸张了
I cannot believe him. I cannot believe this.
搞什么
What the hell?
继续开
All the way!
一辆卡车
A truck?
爸  别告诉我你把钱全砸这车上了
Dad, please tell me you didn't spend our money on this.
他没有  别担心  他花的是我的钱
Oh, no, don't worry, he didn't. He spent my money.
一共150美元
A hundred and fifty bucks of it.
就当透支一下你的固定工资吧
As an advance on your regular paycheck.
-什么固定工资  -以后会还给你的
- What regular paycheck? - Which you will get back.
-什么时候  -别想了  我们破产了
- When? - Never. We're broke.
我就知道
I knew it.
宝贝  能不能请你别挑拨
Sweetheart, could you please not drive a wedge
老板和员工之间的关系
between employer and employee.
等等  我以为我们是合伙人的关系
Hold on. I thought we were partners.
我手头紧  还得给她买毕业舞会的礼服
Look, I came up short, okay? I had to buy her a prom dress.
你不希望我给她买毕业舞会的礼服吗
You want me to deny her a prom dress?
不买也行  反正你不让她带舞伴
You might as well. You denied her a prom date.
才没有  我会陪她一起去
No, I offered to take her and chaperone.
谁想和自己老爸跳舞啊
Nobody wants to go to the dance with their dad.
太奇怪了
It's weird.
问题不在这
It's not the issue.
也许问题就出在这
Well, maybe it should be.
你们就不能放过我吗
Hey, could you guys just get off my case?
你们知道这车上的引擎能卖多少钱吗
You know what the engine on this runs for?
我可以把它拆了  卖零件
I could break it down and strip it for parts.
还有亲爱的  你的短裤一直在缩水
And sweetheart, your shorts are shrinking by the second, okay?
冷水洗  自然风干  拜托了
Cold water, air dry, please.
我觉得她挺性感的
I think she looks hot.
你说什么
What did you say?
一个青春洋溢的少女
Like a hot teenager.
听你说"少女"我真是宽心多了呢
Oh, it's the "teenager" thing that makes it better. Thank you.
我真的不是那个意思
It didn't sound like what it meant.
跟电路板放一起
That goes by the circuit boards.
把蔡司镜头放那吧
Put the zeiss lenses over there.
爸  拜托  你不能再往废品上砸钱了
Dad, please. You can't keep spending money on junk
你只是把一种废品变为另一种废品
just so you can turn it into different junk.
在这里没有东西是"废"的
We do not use the "J" word in here.
那是超级单路影院投影机  非常稀有
That is a super simplex theater projector. It's very rare.
微笑领航员怎么样
What about the Smilepilot?
或者我发明的
Or the exer-mower
运动除草机呢  都是超时代的发明
that I invented? Simply ahead of their time.
对  就像那台所谓的看门机器狗一样
Yeah, like the alleged guard-dawg.
你惹他生气了
You're gonna get him upset.
凯德  凯德
Hey, Cade! Cade!
这东西还有用吗
This thing still work?
-没用  -有用
- No! - Yes.
当然有用  而且依旧是划时代的技术
Yes, and still groundbreaking.
回去躺在躺椅上
Go back there and lay on the recliner
等它给你送冰啤过来就可以了
and just wait for a cold one.
哥们  别搞破坏了
Dude, stop breaking stuff.
最终通知  迟付通知  逾期未付
Final notice, late notice, past due.
来  过来
Come on, come on.
把酒给老爹拿来  过来
Bring daddy the alcohol. Come on.
别人给你寄的这些破烂是什么啊
I mean, what is all this crap people send you?
那个是随身听  那个是八轨磁带
That's a discman and that's an 8-track tape.
-听音乐用的  -没听说过
- Music. - Never heard of it.
那个修好可以卖100块  那个250
Look, I fix that, it's 100 bucks. I fix that, it's $250.
你要是摔得不重
If I would have been able to fix that
我把它修好了
before you broke it even more,
应该值20块
it would have been 20 bucks.
只要你拿到奖学金
Those stuffs gonna put you to college,
这些够你念大学了
as long as you land one of those scholarships.
它送一趟东西一般大概要多久  平均多久
What's the estimated time of arrival, usually? Average?
等下  它只会把啤酒拿到你附近吗
Wait. So it just brings the beer near you?
这是玩我吧
That's the trick?
-它也有点不足  -是啊是啊
- It's got a couple kinks, man. - Yeah.
爸爸  你有想过
Dad, you think maybe some things
有些东西就不应该发明出来吗
should never be invented?
没想过  那是思想倒退
No, I don't. That's backwards thinking.
这是技术的圣殿
This is a temple of technology.
这里是个神圣的地方
You guys are standing in a holy place.
你们觉得怎么样
What do you think?
来看看这么大的地方
Why don't you look at all of this?
都可以归你所有  这片地怎么样
This could be yours. What about this land?
紫色食人怪回来了  而且似乎要大干一场
Purple people eater's back and she looks hungry.
难道不觉得惊喜吗
Isn't this incredible?
-我就知道你们会喜欢这里的  -你们
- I knew you would like it. - Hey, you!
这房子是我的  不卖的
I own this house! It's not for sale!
你已经六个月未付贷款了  耶格先生
Six months late on payments, Mr. Yeager.
而且我还看到你从电线杆那边偷电
And I see you stealing power at the pole.
与你无关
Hey, that's not your concern.
先生  你想参观这处房产吗
Sir, do you wanna see the property?
当然
Sure.
我先带你去看看后院埋的买家们
I'm more than happier to give you a tour, show you other buyers I buried in the back,
然后再打爆你的头
then I'll crack your head open like an egg!
-后退  -他疯了
- Stay back! - He's crazy.
我警告过你别再过来
I told you don't come back here anymore.
你等着  我叫我哥来把你打的满地找牙
I will have my brother come back and beat your ass.
-别冲着我来  -有种你来打我啊
- Don't you start with me. - Why don't you do it yourself?
下次我叫警察一起来
And I'll bring the police when I come, too!
我哥哥可不是吃素的
My brother ain't no joke!
谁啊  杰瑞
Who, Jerry?
你把那个胖子拽来呀
You bring his big ass up here,
就他那身板儿  还没等挤下车
he's gonna be huffing and puffing
就已经喘不上来气儿了
before he can squeeze out of that car!
你要是敢动我家的房子
You back out on my grass,
那就摊上大事儿了
you're gonna be in big trouble!
你把杰瑞叫来
You tell Jerry to come see me.
我告诉他花儿为什么这样红
I'll give him some pecan pie.
她竟敢撞坏栅栏
She smashed through the fence?
凯德  放轻松
Cade, relax.
再这样下去该动脉梗死了
You're going to have an aortic infarction.
那是什么玩意儿
What is that?
好像是心脑血管疾病吧
I think it's a brain heart attack.
我早就得过了
Yeah, I've had one already.
我们在偷电吗
So we are stealing power now?
不  只是向邻居借用一下
No, we're borrowing it from the neighbors.
干的漂亮  你真行
Great. That's awesome.
一旦我毕业了  离开你了
Once I graduate and I'm gone,
谁来照顾你
who's gonna take care of you?
是你在照顾我吗
Oh, you take care of me?
是谁教你焊接的
Who taught you how to solder a circuit?
还有编程  法式编发
Or write a program? Or French braid your hair?
玩橄榄球  是我  都是我教的
Or throw a spiral? Me. That's what I do.
谁教你不用番茄酱做饭的
Who taught you how to cook without ketchup,
谁教你收支平衡的
or balance your checkbook?
是谁在一直扮演成年人的角色
Who always has to be the grownup around here?
好吧  你说的有道理  我承认
All right, you got a point, okay?
可这说明我们是好伙伴
But that means we're a great team.
我知道最近这些日子糟透了
And I know it's been sucky around here lately.
但是情况一定会好转的  宝贝
But we're gonna be fine, sweetie.
你要有信心  好吗
You just gotta keep believing, okay?
伟大的发明家都有坚定的信念
I mean, that's what great inventors do.
我向你保证  总有一天
I promise you, one day,
我会创造出能够举足轻重的东西
I'm gonna build something that matters.
我相信你  爸爸
I believe you, dad.
你妈妈会为你感到骄傲的
You know, your mom would be very proud of you.
一切都会好起来的
It's going to be okay.
散开  向右前进
Spread out! Push right!
行动  行动
Roll, roll, roll, roll.
两分钟  两分钟
Give me two. Give me two.
占领海岸  小心行事
Take the beach, nice and easy.
释放微型无人机
Release the mini-drones.
墓风部队
报告毒蛇  已发现老鹰
Vipers. Eagle in sight.
目标确认
Cleared hot.
发现热信号  船头附近的第二个烟囱
Got a heat sig. Second stack. Closest to the bow.
掠食者0-1
Predator 0-1.
锁定目标区域
Captured target area.
安装炸药
Set charges.
长官  长官  我是枪手0-1
Leader, leader, this is Gunfighter 0-1.
老鹰向内移动  二层甲板
Eagles moving internal. Second deck.
青蛙男83  青蛙男83
Frogman 83, Frogman 83.
从顶层突入
Breached site on rooftop.
从顶层突入  E队待命
Breached site on rooftop. Have Echo platoon on standby.
通知直升机我们正在向外移动
Let the helo know we're moving external!
A队  占据左舷
Alpha, take port.
B队  占据右舷
Bravo, take starboard.
右移  右移
Shift right. Shift right.
炸开烟囱
Cracking steel!
不
No!
进攻  进攻  进攻
Hit him, hit him, hit him!
开火
Fire.
导弹已发射  注意危险
Missiles out. Danger close.
他跑了  快追
He's running! Move!
目标正在移动  目标正在移动
He's on the run! He's on the run!
不要  求你们了
No! Please!
别开枪
Hold your fire.
别  别开枪
Hold! Hold fire!
你们没看见吗  我已经受伤了
Can you not see? I've been injured.
围住他  围住他
Box him in. Box him in.
我是医疗官救护车  你们的盟友
Medical officer Ratchet! I'm a friend!
我是汽车人
I'm an Autobot!
那你为什么还要跑
Then why are you running?
擎天柱给我发了预警信息
Optimus sent this distress message.
呼叫所有汽车人
Calling all autobots.
我们现在是攻击目标
We are under targeted attack.
停止与人类的所有联系
Cease all contact with humans.
我们都躲起来了
We're all hiding.
所有的汽车人都在逃亡
All autobots are being hunted.
危在旦夕
We're all in danger.
我妹妹在芝加哥遇难了
I lost a sister in Chicago.
别指望我同情你
You'll get no sympathy from me.
你们人类是怎么了
What's wrong with you humans?
不要  求你们了
No! Please.
暂停射击  暂停射击
Check fire, check fire!
我来处理他
He's mine now.
禁闭
Lockdown.
汽车人  霸天虎
Autobots, Decepticons.
就跟孩子一样  总是打个不停
Like little children, always fighting.
给这世界添乱
Making a mess out of the universe.
还要我出面替他们擦屁股
Then I've got to clean it up.
你想活命  只有一个办法
There is one way you survive.
告诉我他藏在哪
Tell me where he's hiding.
擎天柱在哪儿
Where is Optimus Prime?
休想
Never.
那你也休想活命了
Never is here.
我得说  你们的工作非常出色
I must say, it is remarkable,
在你接管部门之后
really astounding the success that the CIA has had
中情局取得了前所未有的成功
since you have taken operational control,
所以总统派我来请你
and so the president has asked me to ask you
还有他
to ask him,
邀请你们两个
to invite you both, uh,
到白宫坐一坐  聊一聊
over to the white house just to powwow,
给我们大概讲一下
where we get maybe some more specifics about how
你们是怎么追捕霸天虎的余党的
exactly you're hunting the enemy Decepticons left.
我干这行有两年了
I've had my desk for two years.
而艾丁格先生已经在这里工作了25年
Mr. Attinger has been here for 25.
我从来不询问他的工作细节
He runs the projects where I don't ask for specifics.
所以才叫黑色行动
That's why they're called black ops.
所以我们晚上才睡得着
And why we all sleep better at night.
了解了  这很好啊  那么
Check. That is great. So, um...
有什么猛料吗  进展的怎么样
Any dirt on that? Uh, how, uh, that's going?
非常顺利
Outstanding.
很好  太好了
Great. Oh, great.
等的就是这句  总统会很高兴的
I was hoping to hear that. The president will be pleased.
那个  我实话跟你们说
Cause, I'll tell you right now,
我这个幕僚长周一才刚上任
I've only been chief of staff since Monday,
但我对外星人打仗那些事儿还是挺了解的
um, but I do know that the alien war stuff,
他们  工作中就属他们最有趣了
these are... These are the only fun meetings.
你知道我的工作不是取悦总统
Look, I'm not here to entertain the president,
但是你可以告知他战争将会很快结束
but you may tell him that the war will be over soon.
很快结束  以防他问起
be over... In case he asks,
我需要明确记下你的答复
I just like to have an exact quote.
"战争将会很快结束"
"War will be over soon."
这很好啊  多好的消息
That is great. Such good news.
还有  总统期望
And, um, the president would, I know, just love...
非常非常期望
Really, really love
跟他碰面  其实不能叫碰面
to press the flesh... Not flesh, obviously,
就是跟他拍张照什么的
but just maybe get a shot with, um...
是天柱大人  天柱先生
Is it lord Prime? Sir Prime?
可以在空军一号上
We could bop on air force one.
就简单见个面  速战速决
It'd be just a quick bop, then we just bop in and bop back.
-别让总统抱太大希望  -好吧
- I wouldn't get his hopes up on that one. - Okay.
擎天柱
He's called Optimus Prime.
是外星战士  是违法的
Alien combatant. Here illegally.
他们不是我们的盟友吗  为什么违法
But aren't they our friends? Why?
因为只要他们一天不消失
Because our world will never truly be safe
我们的世界就不会真正的安全
till all of them are gone.
我还以为我们可以
Oh. Well, I would hope we could do
举行一个正式的告别仪式
a much more ceremonial farewell.
毕竟我们的军队
Especially since our military
曾与他们有过亲密合作
has worked so closely with them.
-但是你这样说  -这不是他们的星球
- Until you. - It's not their planet.
从来都不是
Never was.
该物归原主了
Time we take it back.
好了  来吧  加把劲儿
All right, come on. Come on.
很好  很好
Yes. Yes.
非常好
Yes.
你做到了
Oh, there you go.
别  把住啊
No, hold it.
别抖
Stop shaking!
为什么发抖啊  你又不用担心温饱
Why are you shaking? You have the job!
你忘记吃晚饭了
You forgot to eat dinner!
知道我为什么担心了吧
You see why I worry?
对不起  宝贝  我
Look, sorry, sweetie, I...
我差一点就成功了
I almost got it working right.
那个  我完成了作业也结束了期末考试
So, listen, I'm done with homework and set with finals,
所以我想跟朋友们开车出去玩儿会
so I was just gonna take a little drive with some friends
行吗
if that was okay with you.
不找男朋友  我知道  先毕业再说
No boys, I know. Graduate first.
那是
Exactly.
你知道就咱家有这条规矩吧
You do know no one else has this rule, right?
规矩  别说这么难听
Rule? Don't make it sound harsh, okay.
这是智慧
It's wisdom.
而且也没必要开车出去玩儿
I don't think we need to be driving around
都7点45了  天快黑了
It's already like quarter to eight. It's almost dark.
斯帕德  你能消停会儿吗
Spud, will you stop it?
你知道我毕业的时候在干什么吗
You know where I was for my graduation?
知道  跟我这个错误在一起
Yes. With me, the mistake.
你是惊喜  泰莎  最美妙的事
The surprise, Tess. And the best thing that ever happened.
我们看起来不幸福吗
Do we look unhappy? Huh?
那是我这一生中最美好的一天
No. It's the greatest day of my life.
你妈妈去世之前我向她保证
I made your mother a promise before she passed.
我们的孩子一定会出席毕业典礼的
Our baby's gonna be at her graduation. That's it.
高中的小伙子什么都不懂
High school boys know nothing.
成熟之后才靠得住
It's only later they turn into men.
所以如果你那时更成熟更明智
So if you were older and wiser,
我就不会出生了
I wouldn't exist.
我不是这个意思
That's not what I meant.
这是个不谈恋爱的家庭
You know, this is a non-dating household, okay?
你不恋爱  我也不恋爱  就是这样
You don't date, I don't date. That's it.
也许你真该去谈一场
Well, maybe you should.
泰莎  别走
Tessa, wait.
泰莎
Tessa?
听我说
Look.
我知道我太严格了  但是我必须这样做
I know I've been on you, okay? But I have to be.
大家都知道  12到17岁是危险期
Twelve to seventeen is the official teenage danger window.
陪你顺利度过这段时间是我的责任
It's my job to get you through it.
你想怎么生气都行
So you can be pissed off all you want.
好吧  你去跟朋友兜风吧
And, yes, you can take a ride with your friends.
好的
Okay.
别熬夜工作
Don't work all night.
记得吃饭
And eat.
生命中最美好的事  艾米丽
Best thing that ever happened, Emily.
她的出现是我生命中最美好的事
She's the best thing that ever happened.
你会为之骄傲的
You'd be proud.
哦  不
Oh, no.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
简直难以置信  老天
Unbelievable. God!
这里面总得有什么东西能补贴下家用
Something in here needs to make this family some money.
来吧  你这老古董
Come on, you old wreck.
审判日到了
Judgment day.
他人呢
Where is he?
我不知道
I don't know.
发现入侵者  发现入侵者
Intruder alert! Intruder alert!
混蛋
Asshole.
我要报警了
I am dialing 911.
泰莎  我算是你叔叔了
Tess, I'm basically your uncle.
你家就是我家
Su casa es mi casa.
我们要失去这个家了
And we're going to lose the casa.
爸爸
Dad!
来了
Coming!
你在折腾激光吗  是的话我就不进来了
Are you working with lasers? If so, I'm not coming in.
你们绝对没见过这样的卡车
You guys have never seen a truck like this before.
快进来  锁上门
Get in here. Lock that door.
这门连锁都没有
It doesn't have a lock.
快看这个散热器上的洞  看看这个大小
Look! Look at the hole in the radiator. Look at the size of it.
有东西在这上面炸了个洞
Something blew a hole in it!
是又如何
Yeah, so?
这不是一般的钢
It's not normal steel.
引擎里面有块弹片
The shrapnel in the engine,
阻断了所有的线路连接
it ripped all the connections apart.
瞧这个  只有我这么聪明的人才能想到
And watch. And this took some Cade genius.
你们肯定会喜欢这个
You are gonna love this.
我把这个和工作电源连通的时候
When I hook this back to a working battery...
呼叫...
Calling all...
呼叫所有汽车人
Calling all autobots.
没错
Oh, yeah.
我觉得这根本就不是辆卡车
I don't think it's a truck at all.
我想我们刚找到了个变形金刚
I think we just found a Transformer.
变形...
Tran... ugh!
-紧急撤离  -等等  伙计们
- Evacuate! - Wait! Guys!
爸爸  你疯了吗
Dad, are you out of your mind?
你不能把这东西留在这
You need to get that thing out of here.
别担心  我在里面干了一晚活都没事
You don't have to worry. I've been in there working all night, I'm fine.
那不是辆卡车  好吗  你说得对
You know what? That's not a truck, okay? You're right.
那是个外星杀人机器
It's an alien killing machine.
哥们  车都报废了
Dude. It's DOA. Jesus.
彻彻底底地报废了
It's been recalled, totaled, done.
听着  你该打那个电话
So, listen, there's a number that you call.
你应该要打给政府
You're supposed to call the government.
现在美国人都这么干
It's the American thing to do.
好了  你打了电话
Here we go. You're supposed to call,
如果真的是外星人
and if it ends up being alien,
你就能赢得两万五千美金
then you win $25,000.
这赢不了钱的
You don't win money.
如果抓到活的
And if you can capture it live...
就像抓瞪羚一样
like tag it like a wild wildebeest,
那你就能拿到十万美金
then you get $100,000.
爸爸  我们快去打电话
Dad, we are making the call.
-我是这么听说的  -我看过那个广告
- I heard that. - I've seen the commercial.
他们没这么说  没有保证
They don't say that. That's not a guarantee.
-我是这么听说的  -我看过那个广告
- I heard that. - I've seen the commercial.
他们没这么说  没有保证
They don't say that. That's not a guarantee.
你觉得格雷格会骗我吗
You think Greg would lie to me?
如果那真是芝加哥战役里的变形金刚
Look, if that's a transformer there from the battle of Chicago,
我得知道他们是怎么运作的
I need to know how it works.
我是个发明家  这将是我的突破口
I'm an inventor. This could be a game changer for me!
如果我在我的发明上运用他们的技术
If I can apply that technology to my inventions,
这辈子都衣食无忧了
we'd never have to worry about money again.
你之前还不是这么说
I've heard that before.
两万五千美金啊  我的学费不愁了
Twenty-five grand! It pays for my college.
房子也不愁了
It pays for the house.
再说  你是花我的钱买的那辆卡车
Besides, you used my money to buy the truck, right?
所以理论上来说  那是我的卡车
So technically, that's my truck.
你说是不是
Don't you think?
你也签了合同
You also signed a contract
同意一切以研究室为首位
regarding all research lab I.P.
什么研究室  哥们  这就是个谷仓
Research lab? It's a barn, dude.
你签的合同  你又想反悔了
You signed it and now you're competing.
你的所有点子都归我所有
Any idea of yours is mine.
你的任何想法都属于我
Any thought you have, I own it,
所以你人都是我的
so basically, I own you.
没什么人是谁的吧
I don't think you can own someone.
那是好多年前的事了  连德州都不兴这套了
That was, like, a while ago, even in Texas.
好了  把喷枪拿过来
All right. Bring the torch over
帮我扶一下轮臂
and help me with the pulley arm.
我觉得弹片废掉了动力源
I think the shrapnel took out its power core.
还有泰莎  看到了吗
Oh, and, Tessa, you see this?
外星杀人机器会让我这么做吗
Would an alien killing machine let me do that?
电话我会打的
Look, I'll make the call.
我们会拿到钱  但先让我看看我是不是对的
We'll get the money. Just first let me see if I'm right.
你想躲房子里  躲着吧
You want to hide in the house? Go ahead.
好的
Okay.
开工了  轮臂
Let's go. Pulley arm.
简直不敢相信
I can't believe him!
那是什么  看着像颗导弹
What is that? Looks like a missile.
就是导弹
It is! Whoa!
爸爸
Dad!
客厅里有颗导弹
There's a missile in the family room!
我的...
Holy...
我要杀了你
I'll kill you!
不  不
No! No!
爸爸  有颗导弹...
Dad, there's a missile in...
我要杀了你  退后
I'll kill you! Stay back!
-别开枪  别开枪  -去报警  快跑
- Oh, no. Don't shoot. Don't shoot! - Call 911! Run!
卢卡斯  停下
Lucas! Stop!
卢卡斯  别动  冷静下来
Lucas? Don't move, just calm down.
放松  人类
Easy, human.
在这待着  他不会伤到我们的
Stay there. He's not going to hurt us.
武器系统受损了
Weapons systems damaged.
有个导弹击中了你的引擎
A missile hit your engine.
我们帮你清出来了
And we took it out of you.
你伤得很重
You're hurt really bad.
我只是想帮你
I'm just trying to help you.
你现在在我家  我是个工程师
You're in my home now. I'm an engineer.
我叫凯德·耶格
My name is Cade Yeager.
凯德  我欠你个人情
Cade, I am in your debt.
我叫擎天柱
My name is Optimus Prime.
我的汽车人同胞们
My autobots.
他们的处境很危险
They're in danger.
我得走了  我现在得走了
I need to go. I need to go now.
你觉得你能撑多远
How far you think you're gonna get?
泰莎  过来  他需要我们帮助
Tessa, come here. He needs our help.
你怎么了
What happened to you?
人类设的埋伏  陷阱
An ambush. A trap. Set by humans.
我逃了出来  变成了这样
I escaped and took this form.
但你是我们这边的
But you're on our side.
人类为什么要伤害你
Why would humans hurt you?
不是只有人类
They were not alone.
-我的汽车人可以修好我  -好
- My autobots can repair me. - Yeah.
要是你还能找到他们的话
If you can reach 'em.
我来修如何
What about me?
我警告你  地球的信使先生
I warn you, Mr. Messager of earth,
同盟就是合约  而合约
an alliance is a contract, and contracts,
就跟人类一样
like humans,
会有到期的一天
expire.
在这颗星球上  我们有句俗话
On this planet, we have a saying.
"敌人的敌人就是朋友"
"The enemy of my enemy is my friend."
我也有句俗话
I also have a saying.
"我不在乎"
"I don't care."
墨西哥市发生什么了
So what happened in Mexico city?
还以为你抓到他了
I thought you had him.
三处直接伤害  一处致命伤
Three direct hits. A mortal wound.
结果你们的人却让他跑了
Then your men allowed him to escape.
你答应给我的是人工智能
You promised me human intelligence.
或者只是句空话
Or is there such a thing?
你还没告诉过我
You know, you've still never told me.
你为什么要他
Why do you want him?
你替谁效力
Who are you working for?
我去过好多星系  每个物种都和你们一样
Every galaxy I've traveled, all you species are the same.
自以为是宇宙的中心
You all think you're the center of the universe.
真是太无知了
You have no idea.
去五金店  照着清单上买
Go to the hardware store and you get the list.
全买回来
The whole list.
你要试着修好他吗
What, you're going to try and fix him?
他可不是什么火车模型啊  凯德
He's not a model train set, Cade.
的确不是  但他很重要
No, that's right. He's important.
但他对谁重要
Yeah, but important to who.
你不能随便把个外星人关在谷仓里
You can't keep an alien locked up in your barn.
你要拿他干嘛  当玩具玩吗
What you gonna do? Play with him?
-你能冷静点吗  -我在尝试
- Will you calm down? - I'm trying to,
你要拿他干嘛  当玩具玩吗
What you gonna do? Play with him?
-你能冷静点吗  -我在尝试
- Will you calm down? - I'm trying to,
但我刚被十尺高的大炮抵着头
but I just got hit in the head with a ten-foot Cannon!
他要是吃了你  那辆车归我
If he eats you, I get the GTO.
一个字也不能跟别人说  听到了吗
Not a word to anybody. Do you hear me?
一个字都不行
Not a single word.
谁都不行
Nobody.
中央情报局
我们锁定了一个高级目标
I think we have a lock on a high-value target.
特别行动小组已经准备就绪
Special operations group is ready.
什么情况
What do you got?
特别行动组刚接到一个德州帕里斯的来电
Sir, special ops just got a call from Paris, Texas.
符合从墨西哥市离开的那辆卡车
Hard match on the truck seen leaving Mexico city.
太好了  去抓他
Son of a bitch. Let's go get him.
你挨的这下好重啊
Took a hell of a hit, you know.
导弹差点打中你的动力源
The missile just missed your power source.
我们叫它火种
We call it a spark.
里面有我们的生命动力
It contains our life force
和所有的回忆
and our memories.
我们管这叫灵魂
Yeah, we call it a soul.
墓风队走吧
Scramble Cemetery Wind.
感谢你们的辛苦工作  女士们先生们
Thank you for your efforts, ladies and gentlemen.
这间房间要转为机密运行了
This room is going dark.
出口在你们左边
The exit is on your left.
-现在由我接管  -走吧
- I'll take it from here. - Okay, let's go.
我现在在墓风  开始行动
I'm with Cemetery Wind. We're on the move.
我重复  开始行动
Repeat, on the move.
凯德
Cade.
你为什么愿意帮我
Why are you willing to help me?
大概是因为你相信我吧
I guess maybe because you trust me to.
我回来了
I'm back!
去得够久啊
Took you long enough!
我头疼  得去看下医生
My head hurts. I had to go to the doctor.
头上肿了那么大个包
I got a welt on my head
看着像在演《星际迷航》
that makes me look like a fricking Star Trek character.
随便吧
Whatever.
快看  快看
Look! Look!
我们到了
We are on property.
毒蛇十五在天使一号上空
Viper 15 overhead Angels 1.
爸爸
Dad!
耶格先生  我叫詹姆斯·萨沃伊
Mr. Yeager, my name's James Savoy.
我是联邦特工
I'm a federal agent.
我们正在追踪一辆废弃卡车
My men and I are trying to track down an abandoned truck.
你这片地不错
It's a nice spread you got here.
可惜要卖掉了
Too bad she's for sale.
谢谢  但我们不卖
Thanks, but she is not.
你是说那辆卡车吗
That the truck you mean?
恐怕不是
Afraid not.
耶格先生  我们接到某人的电话
You know, Mr. Yeager, we received a call from someone
说到了这辆卡车
concerned about this truck.
麻烦了
Oh, no.
不是你吗
That wasn't you?
我唯一关心的
Thing I'm concerned about
是你未经允许出现在我的地盘上
is you being on my property without permissions.
我们有条规矩专门对付那些惹德州人的人
You know, we got a rule about people messing with people from Texas.
而且我不知道你说的什么卡车
And I don't know what truck you're talking about.
就是害美国人丢掉性命的
The kind that cost American lives.
搜索这些房子
Search the property!
"搜索这些房子"是几个意思
What do you mean, "Search the property"?
你都没有搜查令
You don't have a warrant.
我这张脸就是搜查令
My face is my warrant.
等等  假如你们真的找到了一辆卡车
Wait. But if you guys do find a truck,
我们会拿到奖金的  是吧
we get a reward, right?
毒蛇十五号待命  坐标阿尔法
Viper 15 holding, point Alpha.
盯紧了
Lock it down.
散开  散开  散开
Open, open, open.
注意矮墙  注意矮墙
Short wall. Short wall.
五人已进入  五人已进入
Five in. Five in.
发现入侵者
Intruder alert!
退出此处所
Back away from the premises.
这他妈是什么
What the hell is that?
某个弱智发明的吧
Just some dumb inventor.
安全
Clear.
右侧安全
Clear right.
安全
Clear.
环顾四周  保持警惕
360. 720. Heads on a swivel.
走吧  这里没东西
Let's go. There's nothing here.
没有任何迹象  我们什么也没找到
There's no signs. We got nothing.
长官  我们在垃圾堆里
Sir, we have a live armed missile
发现了枚激活的导弹
in the trash.
激活的
Live?
我还亲手把它搬到垃圾堆里了
I carried that to the trash!
你和我说它是哑弹  老兄
You told me that was a dud, dude.
我有可能被炸死  是吧
I could be dead. Right?
听着
Look.
好吧  没错  我是找到了一辆卡车  行了吧
Okay, yes, I found a truck, all right.
我把它拖回来是为了上面的零件
I towed it back for the parts.
我昨晚把它留在这儿  今早它就不见了
I left it here last night. This morning, it's gone.
离开的时间  去了哪里  我都不知道
When? Where? I don't know.
我对天发誓
I swear to God.
关于他  我知道的就这么多了
That's as much as I know about him.
"他"
"Him."
他说的是"他"
He said, "Him."
他知道那狗娘养的是谁
He knows who the son of a bitch is.
耶格先生
Mr. Yeager.
怎么了
What?
抱歉
Excuse me.
你刚刚说了"他"
You just said, "Him."
拿下他们
Take them down.
什么
What?
放开我
Let me go!
他们不知道卡车的事  我知道
They don't know about the truck! I know!
快放开她
Just let her go.
什么样的人会背叛自己的血肉同胞
What kind of a man betrays his flesh-and-blood brethren
就为了一坨外星金属
for alien metal?
不要让我看见他
Get this guy out of my sight.
滚开
Get off!
放开她  他们不知道卡车的事
Let her go! They don't know about the truck.
好了  上好膛
All right! Load up!
-卢卡斯  是你打的电话  是不是  -搜索周边
- Lucas, you called, didn't you? - Search the perimeter!
不是我  这些可怕的人我一个也不认识
No! I don't know any of these scary guys.
天呐  你在虐待一个女人
Oh, God! You're manhandling a woman!
我要狠狠揍你一顿
I'll kick your ass!
放开她
Let her go!
爸爸
Daddy!
-你哪儿也不能去  -放开我
- You're not going anywhere. - Let me go!
爸爸
Daddy!
不行  你们不能带走我
No! You're not taking me anywhere!
我是美国公民
I'm an American!
放轻松  甜心
Easy, sweetheart.
好吧  好吧  好吧
Okay, okay, okay.
行了  好了
All right. Okay.
行了  我错了
All right. I was wrong.
萨沃伊
Savoy.
利用他女儿
Use the girl.
天哪
Oh, my God!
现在  你有十秒钟
Now, you got ten seconds.
卡车在哪里
Where's the truck?
怎么  难道你们打算朝我女儿开枪吗
What, you're gonna shoot my little girl?
假如有必要的话
If I have to.
求求你们别杀我
Please don't shoot me.
我真的不知道  我知道的都说了
Look, I don't know. I told you everything that I know!
他走了  他离开了
He's gone. He left.
他之前就在谷仓里的  我对天发誓
He was in the barn, I swear to God!
快放开她
Just let her go!
求求你了  求求你了
Please, please.
他之前就在里面的
He was in there!
放她走
Let her go!
还剩七秒
Seven seconds.
我说的是实话  他之前就在里面的
I'm telling you the truth! He was in there!
爸爸
Dad!
让他快放开我女儿
Tell him to get away from my little girl now!
爸爸
Dad!
你再碰她我就杀了你
You touch her and I'll kill you!
你还剩两秒钟
You got two seconds.
我要听实话
I need the truth.
求你了
Please.
杀了她
Shoot her.
我在这
Here I am!
趴下
Get down!
凯德  他们会杀掉你们的
Cade! They're going to kill you!
快离开这里
Get out of here!
向右推进  朝房子前进
Push right! Headed to the house!
快  快点  快上车  走吧
Come on. Hurry up! Get in the car! Let's go!
爸爸  快上车
Daddy, get in the car!
周边小队注意  擎天柱朝你们那边去了
Perimeter, Optimus moving your way!
怎么回事宝贝  他们是谁
What's happening, baby? Who are they?
那辆卡车  他们想要那辆卡车
It's the truck. They want the truck!
"他们是谁"  你又是谁
"Who are they?" Who are you,
你喊谁"宝贝"呢
and who are you calling "baby"?
我知道你们听见我说话了
I know you heard me.
-我是她男朋友  -他是我男朋友
- I'm her boyfriend! - He's my boyfriend!
什么
What?
你才不是她男朋友呢
You're not her boyfriend!
他的名字叫肖恩  是个车手  爸爸
His name's Shane and he drives, dad.
那些都是什么车啊
What kind of cars are those?
好吓人
They're so scary!
后面又来了一辆
There's another one coming up the back!
你得在玉米田里甩掉他们
You gotta try to lose them in the cornfield!
他们从后面追上来了  快开
He's coming up behind us! Go!
毒蛇十五号  燃油不足  即刻返航
Viper 15, running on fumes. RTB.
他们要包抄我们
They've got us cornered!
小心  小心  小心
Watch out, watch out, watch out!
耶格先生
Mr. Yeager,
我并不想在这种情况下见面的  明白吗
this is not how I wanted us to meet, okay?
我叫肖恩  我是个完完全全的...
I'm Shane, and I'm a completely...
我不想跟你说话  好好开车
And I am not talking to you! Drive the car!
小心  小心
Watch out! Watch out!
开几枪警告他们
Throw 'em some warning shots!
天啊  我居然能开这么好
Man, I don't know how I'm driving this good.
像是升了一级
It's like, today I've gone to a whole other level.
看路  集中注意力  别说话了
Road, focus! Stop talking!
肖恩  小心
Shane, look out!
其实主要是我的错  明白吗
This may be primarily my fault, okay.
他们说了会带支票过来的
They said they were gonna bring a check!
谁知道来的是敢死队
I didn't know they were gonna send a death squad!
抓紧了
Hang on!
冠军产生了
Hey, we got ourselves a winner!
唐赢得了第一名
Don's got it over here.
小心
Look out!
我们甩掉他们了
We lost them!
干得好  玉米田里来的陌生人
Good job, stranger from the cornfields!
那些吓人的车又回来了
The scary cars are back.
在工厂甩掉他们  肖恩
Lose them at the factory, Shane!
我还以为你会开车呢  快
I thought you knew how to drive this thing! Go!
我觉得钱是拿不到了
I don't think we're gonna get that money.
应该是拿不到了
Doesn't seem like it.
凯德
Cade!
引他们上楼
Take 'em upstairs!
我们到五楼甩掉他们
We're losing them on the fifth floor.
-玩那一招  肖恩  -你懂我
- Do that thing, Shane! - You know it.
你们什么意思  哪一招
What do you mean? What thing?
我们马上要干的事  可能会有点吓人
What we're about to do is gonna be kind of scary.
把你们的枪掏出来  杀了他们
Take out your guns and shoot them!
他们在朝我们开枪
They're shooting at us!
泰莎  抓住手刹[小弟弟]
Tessa, grab my stick! Grab my stick!
什么
What?
她的小手干这个最厉害了
She's got the best hands in the business.
准备好了吗  泰莎
Ready, Tess?
拉
Pull!
不不不  不要
No! No! No! No f-ing way!
泰莎  你别想出家门了
Tessa, you are so grounded!
该死  轮圈裂了
Shit! The rim's cracked.
擎天柱
Optimus.
来吧  快  快走
Come on, move! Move!
我的脚卡住了  等等  凯德
My foot's stuck! Wait, Cade!
卢卡斯
Lucas!
等等  等等
Wait! Wait!
卢卡斯
Lucas!
卢卡斯  它在你上面
Lucas, it's above you!
快跑
Run!
快来  上车  快走
Come on, get in, let's go!
你是不是特别想看我现在是什么脸色
I'll bet you wish you could see my face right now.
卢卡斯  要抛下他吗
Lucas, we just left him?
他死了
He's gone.
失去了朋友节哀吧
My deepest sympathies for the loss of your friend.
别动  我看有没有人跟踪
Stay here till I'm sure we weren't followed.
我们都是目标了
We are all targets now.
所以现在我们就躲着吗  这就是计划吗
So we're hiding out now? That's the plan?
难道我们要听一个卡车的命令吗
We're taking orders from a truck?
你有什么更好的主意吗
Well, you got a better idea?
离她远点  小子  不要...
Hey, move away from her, kid. Don't...
别碰她  明白吗  不准
Keep your hands off her. All right? No.
你被德州的一个车库发明家狠揍了一顿
You got your ass kicked by a garage inventor from Texas.
会在你简历上记上这一笔的
That goes on your resume.
没错  你们所有人都是
Yeah, it goes on all of yours, too!
你觉得我有心情听你废话吗
Do I look like I'm in the mood for any of your shit today?
华盛顿方面以为我们在追霸天虎
Washington thinks we were chasing a decepticon target,
但是不找到耶格
but our story falls apart
故事就穿帮了
if we don't find this Yeager family first.
是啊  假如他去找警察或者联调局呢
Yeah, well, what if he goes to the cops or the FBI?
他们知道要把他交过来的
They know to hand him over.
他的生活已经没得过了
His world as he knows it is gone.
往好的一方面想  你俩总算见面了
Well, bright side, you guys met.
他是哪里人
Where is he from?
我告诉过你了  他是德州的一个车手
I told you, he's a driver from Texas.
德州
Texas?
德州都柏林  德州三叶草吗
Where, Dublin, Texas? Shamrock, Texas?
他怎么一股爱尔兰味
So why does he sound like a Leprechaun?
在爱尔兰说这话的话你会被狠揍一顿的
You'd get your ass kicked in Ireland for saying that.
我们不在爱尔兰  小可爱  在德州
Well, we're not in Ireland, lucky charms. We're in Texas.
他是车手
And so he drives?
这是什么意思  他是开车的
What do you mean, he drives?
是说  他靠这个为生
Like, for a living?
是的
Yeah.
至少他能养活自己
At least he makes a living.
谢谢
Thank you.
听着  我参加拉力赛
Look, I race rally cars.
一个车手
One driver.
一个领航员
One navigator.
她
Her.
顺便一说  我是完全合法的
By the way, I'm totally legit.
我刚刚被红牛车队选上了
I just got picked up by red bull.
还有告诉您一声
And just so you know,
我的全部家当都在那辆车上了
my life savings was in that car back there.
这不可能
This is not happening.
绝对可能
Oh, it definitely is.
你多大了
How old are you?
20.
她才17岁
She's a 17-year-old girl.
这事只有两个解决办法
So we can work this two ways.
一   我给你一拳
One, I punch you right in the mouth
你报警抓我
and you call the police on me.
-爸  -或者二
- Dad. - Or two,
我直接报警抓你
I just call the cops on you
因为这是违法的  她是未成年人
because this is illegal. She's a minor.
我们是受罗密欧与茱丽叶法保护的
We're protected by the Romeo and Juliet laws.
我们交往的时间很长了
We dated for a little while
-我二年级他四年级  没事的  -当然有事
- I was a sophomore, and he was a senior. It's fine.  - No, it's not fine.
我们是青少年  正在相恋
We've got a preexisting juvenile foundational relationship.
-条令第22章011条  -什么
- Statute 22.011. - What?
德州法律吗
Texas statute?
-真有这么一条吗  -是的
- That a real law? - Yep.
罗密欧和茱丽叶是吗
Romeo and Juliet, huh?
你知道她们俩的结局吗
You know how those two ended up?
相爱了
In love.
死掉了  你父母知道这事吗
Dead. Do your parents know about this?
你父亲同意你和17岁的姑娘恋爱吗
Is your dad okay with you dating a 17-year-old girl?
我5岁的时候他走了
He took off when I was five,
再遇到他我会问问的
but if I ever bump into him, I'll ask him.
知道吗  泰莎
You know, Tessa,
-我本来很放心你的  -放心我什么
- I trusted you. - To what?
从来不玩不冒险
Never have fun, take a risk,
和你一样当个乖宝宝吗
be a normal teenager, like you?
而且我一直在竭力照顾你
And I have been busting my ass to take care of you.
你把那卡车带回家时
Is that what you were doing
有为我着想吗
when you brought home the truck?
本来你只要报警就行
All you had to do was report it,
现在可好  卢卡斯为此而死了
and now Lucas is dead.
我的人生也完了  谢谢你了
And my life is over. Thank you.
你把我照顾的真好
You've taken real good care of me.
求求你不要开枪
Please don't shoot me!
求你  爸爸
Please! Dad!
他们当时真打算杀了她
They were willing to kill her.
现在也是这么打算的
Then they still are.
是某人在某处下的命令
Somebody somewhere gave that order.
我要找到他的蛛丝马迹
I'm going to find some fingerprints.
请不要这样
Please!
不要
No!
我是汽车人  我是汽车人
I'm an autobot! I'm an autobot!
带上所有觉得有用的东西
Grab whatever you think we can use for supplies.
衣服什么的  还有那台电脑
Clothes, anything. And take that computer.
我们出发
Let's go.
这不太容易
This is not easy.
你也不是一无是处  爸
You know, you don't suck at everything, dad.
什么啊
What the...
我就知道
I knew it.
你跟我说他只是个小人物
You told me he was no one.
现在
Well,
这小人物有了我们的技术
this "No one" Has our tech.
呼叫所有汽车人
Calling all autobots.
哇哦  我的神啊
Whoa! Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
这太疯狂了
That was insane!
很酷但是很疯狂  对吧
It was awesome, but it was insane, right?
耶  太棒啦
Oh, yeah! Hell, yeah!
他回来了  他还活着
He's back! He's alive!
擎天柱来了
Optimus is here!
终于  终于还是有希望了
At last. There is hope after all.
耶
Yeah.
自由星系的领袖回来啦
Mr. Leader of the free galaxy is back.
我就知道你没事  我从没质疑过
I knew you'd make it. I never doubted.
我们收到了你的警告  一直在等待
We got your warning. We've been waiting.
说的没错  开打吧
Hell, yeah. Boom time.
我们又重聚啦
We got the gang back together.
人类要求我们服从他们的规矩
Humans have asked us to play by their rules.
现在规矩变了
Well, the rules have just changed.
人类都是背后捅刀子的小人
Human beings, bunch of backstabbin' weasels.
猎狗  寻找你自己的心海罗盘
Hound, find your inner compass.
忠诚为何物
Loyalty is but a flower
恐惧诱惑之风中  柔柔一朵花
in the winds of fear and temptation.
你说什么乱七八糟的呢
What the hell are you saying?
-这叫俳句  -被废话了
- It's a haiku. - Cut the crap,
要不我就给你喂颗手榴弹
before I drop a grenade down your throat.
试试看  你会付出生命的代价
Try it, you'll be dead.
我求你动手吧  动手吧
Oh, please pull it. Please do it.
那倒给我们省事了
You know what, it'll save us so much time.
觉得
Well, raise your hand
愉快的地球之旅
if you're thoroughly disenchanted
该结束的请举手
with our little pleasant earth vacation.
这偷偷摸摸的是谁啊
So, who's the stowaways?
干嘛呀  别举枪嘛
Oh, whoa, hey, what's with the gun?
住手  猎狗  你也住手
Stop. Hound, both of you.
他们为了救我冒了生命危险
They've risked their lives for mine.
我们欠他们的
We owe them.
没有其他人了吗
So, there's been no sign of any others?
没  就剩我们了
Nada. We are all that's left.
他们正在把我们逐个击破
They're picking us off, one by one.
我们是可悲的落魄四人组
We're the pathetic, dirty foursome.
加你是五人组了
And you make five.
最好就只能到这步吗
So that's our best-case scenario?
汽车人证人保护措施
Autobot Witness Protection?
飚车的
Hey, speed racer,
你想走就直接走
you're welcome to leave anytime.
我说明一下  超级老爸
Well, for the record, superdad,
不是你罩着我
I'm not hiding with you.
是这个大家伙哎
I'm hiding out with that big guy.
先生  您下落不明时
Sensei, with your fate unknown,
大黄蜂暂时担任了领队
Bumblebee has held command,
虽然他完全没有一点
despite his complete and total lack of anything
武士的纪律
resembling warrior discipline.
他简直像个孩子
He's like a child.
这孩子打算揍你一顿
This child is about to kick your ass.
他简直给我们丢脸
He brings us shame.
综合格斗
Cage fight.
自作聪明
Smartass.
他们怎么回事
What's the matter with them?
难道只有我看透了
Am I the lone sage who sees through
他这卖萌的眼神吗  和你很不搭
this puppy-dog eyes act? It's beneath you.
太好了  我一直等他们
Yes, I've been waiting
打个两败俱伤
for them all to dispatch each other,
这样我就能顺利当上老大了
so I could take charge with no trouble at all.
独自一人来去自由
Just me reporting to me.
看来你当老大最好呢
Well, it sure looks like you've been missed.
汽车人  禁闭在追捕我们
Autobots, Lockdown is hunting us
而人类在帮他
and humans are helping.
我们得搞清楚为什么
We need to know why.
听着  我虽然不知道原因
Well, listen, I don't know why,
但我知道这事是谁干的
but I have an idea about who.
我偷来的这个无人机有段突袭汽车人的视频
This drone I stole recorded footage of an autobot raid.
断断续续的  但是能看出发生了什么事
It's in pieces, but watch what happens here.
那是铅足
Oh, that's Leadfoot.
他们扯碎了他
They rip him apart.
太野蛮
Savages.
稍后  一辆车来拖走了他
And later, this truck comes to haul him off.
KSI  智能解决方案
KSI. Kinetic Solutions.
搞国防宇航的  和政府签约
Defense, aerospace, government contracts.
是他们设计了这架无人机
They designed this drone.
就是说是政府的人在追捕你们
So these government guys just hunt you down,
然后再把你们交给这个KSI
and then pass you off to this KSI?
这个公司的总部在芝加哥
The company is headquartered in Chicago.
他们可能就是被带去那里了
That could be where they were taken.
要进去恐怕免不了战斗
No way to get inside without a battle.
有人类帮忙也许可以
Well, what if you had some human help?
你俩现在是伙伴了吗
What, are you two partners now?
宝贝  知道原因才能赢回我们的生活
Sweety, we need to know why or we'll never get our lives back.
汽车人们  我曾起誓绝不杀人
Autobots, I have sworn to never kill humans.
绝对是个错误
Big mistake.
但如果让我抓住幕后黑手
But when I find out who's behind this,
我一定会杀了他
he's going to die.
现在外面正全力搜捕我们
There's a full-on manhunt out for us,
所以我们得定几条新规矩
so we have some new rules.
所有警方的人都是敌人
Anyone who has got a badge is not our friend.
我们要分头进攻
We're gonna divide and conquer.
你俩就负责偷取食物和必需品
You two in charge of stealing food and the essentials.
其他的不要参与
And nothing else.
芝加哥KSI总部坚如堡垒
Chicago KSI headquarters is like a fortress.
我会想办法溜进他们的军事最高机密区
I'm gonna find a way into their top-secret military wing.
看有没有他们和政府的把柄
Find something to blackmail this company and the government.
我们要赢回自由
We're gonna get our freedom back.
早上好  乔伊斯先生
Good morning, Mr. Joyce.
那是什么声音
What was that sound?
那正是
That's "The" Sound.
您要的声音
That you asked for.
不  我要求的是无限感  至高无上感
No, I asked for boundless. Transcendent.
当你穿过这栋楼的门
When you walk through a door in this building,
要有种踏进了未来的感觉
it should sound like you've stepped into the future.
这是现在
Present.
大声说
Say it.
这是未来
Future.
过去已然是历史  现在也正在过去
The past is history. The present is past.
而当下属于未来
The future is now.
我为什么联系不到你
Why can't I get in touch with you?
你难道没意识到北极的发现意味着什么吗
Don't you realize what the arctic find means?
你知道我们小时候都听过的
You know that story we were all told as children
上百万年前一个巨大的小行星撞击地球
about a giant asteroid that struck the earth
才导致恐龙灭绝的故事吧
millions of years ago and wiped out the dinosaurs?
好像知道
Vaguely.
我们错了
We were wrong.
这机械才是它们灭绝的原因
This metal caused the great extinction.
过程和方式我还不能确定
How and why, I can't yet say.
碳14测定它的年代大约在
But carbon dating puts it at
公元前六千五百万年
65 million years B.C.
你让我们挖掘的这个矿石
This ore you've got us digging for
比你以为的要危险的多
is a lot more dangerous than you think.
而且我的人
And my people...
达西
Darcy,
我看只是你不太了解状况
I think that you've been out in the field for far too long.
恐龙的事不如放在晚餐时讨论吧
Why don't we discuss dinosaurs over dinner?
-吃肋排去  -没戏
- Ribs? - Not a chance.
你根本不了解状况
You have no idea what's been happening here.
我们马上就要飞跃了
We're about to make the quantum leap.
一种稀土金属
A rare-earth metal.
分子组成极不稳定
Molecularly unstable.
工业用途为零
Industrial uses, none.
接着外星人来到了地球
And then the aliens came.
我们才发现了其间的联系
And we made the connection.
他们正是由它组成的
It's what they're made of.
这就是我们的圣杯
It's the holy grail.
变形元素  我们起的名字
"Transformium." That's what we're calling it.
贴切顺口
Focus-grouped. Catchy.
注册商标吧
Trademarked.
这是核裂变之后
This is the greatest advance in modern physics
现代物理学最大的发现
since the splitting of the atom.
这是可编程物质
It's programmable matter.
现在我们绘制出了它的基因组
And now, we've mapped its genome.
-是我  -你绘制出了它的基因组
- I. - Now you've mapped its genome.
现在我们就可以开始
And now we can begin to give it
给它指令了
instructions.
这个相当不错
This is extremely good.
瞧这个
Watch this.
可以变成任何东西
We can change anything into anything.
好感性的金属  不是吗
Sensual, almost. Don't you think?
你喜欢音乐吗
Do you like music?
胶囊音箱
The pill.
或者是更暴力点的
Perhaps something a little more violent?
老天  你做到了
Oh, my God. You've done it.
在航空宇宙中  军队里
In aerospace, the military...
我们将拥有整个机器人市场
We will own the entire robotics industry.
所有的探究
All exploration.
海洋  宇宙  一切
The oceans. Space. Everything.
温布利  这是什么
Wembley. What is this?
是你要的那个水母广告
The jellyfish commercial that you wanted.
你说他们充满肉欲
You said they were
却又危险  就像女人一样
erotic yet deadly, like women.
我没说过这种话
I never said that.
-你说了  -我没说
- Yes, you did. - No, I didn't.
你肯定说了  你当时在讲你前女友
I definitely heard you said 'cause you were talking about your ex-girlfriend,
说她很性感  但是个贱人
who was sexy, but a bitch.
参观期间不要吃东西
Please don't eat on the tour.
是她吗
Is that her?
我找到几箱衣服
Hey, I found a whole bunch of boxes of clothes.
亲爱的  你来拿几条长裤吧
So, sweetie, you can get some long pants,
那种宽宽松松的长裤
nice, loose-fitting ones,
把你这些短到不行的短裤扔掉
and lose the short shorts, okay?
你们搞到了什么
What'd you guys get?
是蛋白质粉
It's protein.
我说了只拿必需品
Look, I said the essentials, okay?
说得容易  我们差点被抓
It wasn't easy. We almost got caught.
你偷了瓶漱口水
You stole mouthwash?
我跟你女儿亲热的时候得保持口气清新
I like to be fresh when I'm making out with your daughter.
好好笑
That's funny.
这辈子都不可能
Yeah, that's not happening ever.
这辈子吗
Ever?
只是我们的军方模型机  惊破天
This is our military prototype, Galvatron.
我不懂了
I don't understand it.
这已经是第五次尝试了
This is the fifth iteration.
他怎么还是这种鬼样子
Why does he keep turning out like this?
只是最后润色上有点问题
It's just some bugs in the final render.
我是按擎天柱设计的惊破天
I modeled Galvatron after Optimus Prime.
为什么总是像威震天
Why does he keep looking like Megatron?
润色步骤即将结束  做好准备
Rendering sequence is almost finished. Stand by.
那么简单的编程
Simple coding.
算法
Algorithms!
还有数学
Math!
为什么总不能按照构想
Why can't we make what we want to make,
造出我们想要的
the way we want to make it?
为什么
Why?
哪个顾客愿意买这张苦瓜脸
And does that look like a consumer-friendly face to you?
胸前那个大洞是怎么回事
And what about that big hole in the chest?
看着挺牛逼  我喜欢
I think it's bad-ass. I like it.
-相当喜欢  -我不喜欢
- Love it. - Well, I hate it.
他来了
Oh, here he is.
光头弗兰肯斯坦博士
That bald-headed Dr Frankenstein.
女士  这都是违法的
Ma'am, this is not legal.
这是非法实验
This is illegal experimentation.
外星人永远不会这么对人类
Aliens would never do this to people!
可能会吃了你或杀了你  仅此而已
Eat you, kill you, maybe, but that's it.
这不对  没人能把我关在盒子里
This ain't right! Nobody puts baby in a box!!
比水刑还糟糕
This is worse than waterboarding!
这位小兄弟在为我们翻译
This little gentleman has been translating for us
从这两个脑袋里提取出的信息
all the information that comes from these two heads.
他们的历史  科技  所有的一切
Their history, their science, everything.
-这是威震天吗  -正是
- Is that Megatron? - Precisely.
你从哪找到的
Where did you get all this?
特别政府合同
Special government contract.
现在我们知道了关于变形金刚的一切
Now we know everything about Transformers.
我们终于能自己建造了
And now at long last we can build them ourselves.
可以造的比他们还好
And we can build them better.
很好  大黄蜂  这样就能混进去了
Yeah, that's good, Bee. That'll get us in.
每天都会运几趟货物
Couple times a day these guys move in vehicle shipments
到KSI里进行扫描
into KSI for something called "Scanning."
到处都是最高警备
Major security all over.
我们的最好机会
Our best shot of getting in
是从后面的机密研究室入口进去
is a back classified research entrance.
我明天和大黄蜂一起去
I'm gonna drive in with bee tomorrow morning.
不好意思
Excuse me.
不许在我面前腻歪
There's no smooching in front of me, okay?
你也太古板了  现在谁还说"腻歪"
You're so square. Who even says "Smooching"?
一点都不尊重人
I tell you, no respect.
有的时候太难沟通了
It's just impossible sometimes.
我跟大黄蜂也经常这样
Yeah. I went through that with Bumblebee.
冷静下来  冷静下来
Calm down. Calm down.
现在这种时候
You know, at a time like this,
现在是要保持冷静  不是耍帅装酷
the idea is to keep cool, not look cool,
干嘛不把墨镜摘了
so why don't you lose the glasses?
大概一个月前
About a month ago,
深更半夜的时候我听到家里有动静
middle of the night, I thought I heard noises in my house.
是你吗
Was that you?
什么  绝对不可能
What? Come on. No way.
别对我撒谎  小子
Don't lie to me, kid.
你看到那边那个拿枪的人了吗
You see that guy with the gun out there?
这里都是拿枪的
There's so many guys with guns.
我们要闯进去都是你的主意
We're about to break in and it's your idea,
我可不在乎
'cause I don't care.
我老了  活够久了
I'm old, I've already lived long enough.
你现在说这些真不是时候  老兄
You are really bad of having these conversations at the wrong time, man.
你想息事宁人  还是想让我大闹一场
You want to come clean or you want me to make a mess?
先生  我能跟你谈一下吗
Sir, can I talk to you for a second, please?
是我  是我
It was me, it was me, it was me, it was me.
对不起  对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
是去扫描的吗
Taking it in for scanning?
好了  可以走了
All right. You're good to go.
我真的会杀了你
I'm literally gonna kill you.
在三号港扫描
Scanning in bay three.
我们将陈旧的外星科技
We took old, alien technology
全方位的加以改善
and made it better in every way.
隆重推出刺叮
Introducing Stinger.
KSI  我们创造世界
KSI. We make the world.
那个机器人好牛逼
That is a bad-ass robot.
看着有点像你啊  大黄蜂
He kind of looks like you, bee.
这里是过去  现在是未来
Here is the past. And now the future.
他们在自己造变形金刚
They're trying to build their own versions.
好吧  至少他们选的颜色更酷
Well, at least they're picking cooler cars than this.
你敢这么跟我说话
You talk to me like that?
大黄蜂  停下
Bee, stop!
知道自作聪明的下场了吧
You see what happens from being a wiseass?
给我下去
Now get out of here.
刺叮  灵感源于大黄蜂
Stinger, inspired by Bumblebee...
但是更加尽善尽美
...but better in every way.
我操
Son of a...
别  别  冷静下来
No, no! You gotta calm down.
他疯了  停下
He's crazy! Stop!
大黄蜂  别犯病了
Bumblebee! Bee, stop going psycho!
我的小娇花啊
My delicate flower,
你一生气我就完全不懂你在说什么了
I can't understand you when you're angry.
说真的  我真的不懂你
Actually, I don't really understand you at all.
我们这个工厂都准备好...
Our entire factory is up and running...
稍等片刻
Excuse me one second. Hey!
说你们呢  修理工
Hey, you two! Grease monkeys.
这里在闹什么
What the hell is going on here? Huh?
这辆古董破车是怎么回事
What's with this vintage crap?
我们不扫描垃圾车
We're not scanning collector car junk.
你以为我们在这里造的是什么
What do you think it is that we make here? Hmm?
是诗歌  我们是诗人
We make poetry. We're poets.
你为我卖命  只能犯一次错  懂了吗
All right? You work for me, you get one mistake. One. Understood?
下不为例  没下次了
It won't happen again. It certainly won't.
赶紧带着这破铜烂铁滚吧
So let's get this pathetic thing out of here.
还有你
And you, too.
非常抱歉  非常抱歉
So sorry. So sorry.
我们继续
Let's move on.
看着他  我去看看
Watch him. I'm going to see what I can find.
安静地离开这里
Quietly get out of here.
我发誓  我发誓
I swear. I swear.
你一生气我就不行了
I can't bear it when you're angry.
你知道我会很伤心
You know how it upsets me.
大黄蜂  你得冷静一下
Bee, you gotta calm down right now.
我特别冷静  老兄
I'm perfectly calm, dude.
深呼吸  想干什么就干什么
You gotta breathe,and just do whatever you do.
我很冷静  很冷静  我碰都不会碰
I'm calm. I'm calm. I'm not even touching it.
我只是碰了一下下  一下下  老天
Okay, I'm barely touching it. I'm barely touching it. Oh, my God.
-现在马上变回车  -你少屁话
- Turn back into a car right now! - Get out of my face, alright.
我们的设计团队从大黄蜂着手
Our design team started with the Bumblebee
但说真的  这外星设计很落后
but really, this alien's design was decrepit
直说吧  简直是老古董
and, let's face it, antique.
这他妈...
What the...
-别当真  大黄蜂  -有点老旧不堪
- Don't take it personally, bee. - Kind of old and ratty.
你是说很丑
You mean ugly.
我靠
Oh, hell, no!
别  别
No! No!
你以为你比我好吗
You think you're better than me!
你碰了什么
What did you touch?
伙计我告诉你了  这不能碰
I told you homeboy, can't touch this.
十五分钟后到我办公室来
My office in 15 minutes.
这里是七号解剖室
This is dissection room seven.
惊破天  报废剖析十二号
Galvatron, render postmortem number 12.
在三十二号事项上
Continued head disfigurement
头部仍有缺陷
at event number 32.
生意谈下来了吗
So what about the deal? Is it done?
拿到火种了吗
Did you get the seed?
等赏金猎人找到擎天柱就能拿到了
We get it when the bounty hunter gets prime.
但现在情况有点复杂
Meanwhile, there has been a complication.
什么
A what?
不  不
No, no.
在KSI  我们说这个词
At KSI, we don't use words like that.
那个私藏汽车人的平民
A civilian harboring the autobots
黑了你的一架迷你无人机
has hacked into one of your mini-drones.
也就是说  他们可能知道你也参与其中了
Meaning, they may know of your involvement.
什么
What?
刚刚很紧张啊
That was a little bit intense.
我需要更多的变形元素
I need more Transformium,
现在就要  来建更多模型机
and I need it now, to build more prototypes.
你跟你的外星赏金猎人说
You tell your alien bounty hunter
我把整个公司都押在这单生意上了
that I have staked my company on this deal.
我只不过是把命搭上了
And I have merely staked my life.
是你来找我的  记得吗
Hey, you came to me on this, remember?
你从中情局退休
You retire from the CIA,
我们公司付你七位数的工资
you get a seven-figure piece of my company,
你我联手改革国防
and you and I revolutionize national defense together.
但是  艾丁格先生  哥们儿
But, Attinger, buddy,
为了咱俩共同的利益
for both our sakes,
你必须给我弄到
you need to deliver
火种
the seed.
我进来了  摄像头清楚吗
I'm in. Can you see my camera?
他们在融化救护车
They're melting Ratchet.
他们杀害了救护车
They slaughtered Ratchet!
我要撕碎他们
I'm gonna tear them apart!
金属
Metal.
只是金属而已  我一直这样看待他们
Just metal. That's what I always thought of them.
但并非如此
Well, they're not.
他们有生命  和我们一样有灵魂
They're living things, with souls like ours.
我曾和一个汽车人说过话
Once, I spoke to one.
你也是研究变形元素的吗
And you're working with Transformium?
是啊  我就是干这个的  没错
Uh, yeah, that's what I do. I am.
我是在外面挖掘它的
I'm out there digging for it.
只是可挖掘的不多了
There's just not much left to find.
你们这么迫切地需要它吗
So that's how badly you boys need more, huh?
都开始融化邪恶的霸天虎了
Reduced to melting evil old Decepticons down.
不  那是汽车人
No. That's an autobot there.
曾为我们战斗过的汽车人
The ones who fought for us.
剩下的交给我了
I've got this taken care of from here.
好的
Right.
同一个名牌在大门刷了两次
Same badge code scanned at two separate gates.
我得马上封锁机密区
I'm having the classified area locked down now.
检查那个人
Check that guy.
站住
Stop right there!
Stop!
不许动
Freeze!
趴在墙上
Up against the wall.
好吧
All right.
商业间谍
Corporate espionage.
这可是项重罪  耶格先生
That's a very serious crime, Mr. Yeager.
我要找律师
Look, I want a lawyer.
执法机关  我能信任的人
The justice department. Somebody I can trust.
不要你公司的人  要政府的人
Not from your company, from the government.
耶格先生
Mr. Yeager,
你觉得我是为谁工作的
who do you think I work for?
你是为了保护家人  令人钦佩
You're trying to protect your family, that's admirable.
我是为了保护国家
I'm trying to defend
在与外星人的战争中不受侵害
the nation from alien war.
我们已经见识过了那种战争
We've had a taste of what that looks like,
绝不容许再有这样的事发生
and we are not gonna tolerate another. Now...
这次谈话有两种结果
There is a version of this conversation
一种是你可以回到你的仓库
where you get to go back to your barn,
你的女儿光荣毕业
your daughter gets to graduate with honors,
你的生活也能恢复原状
and life as you know it will go on.
你根本不知道你卷入了什么事
You have no idea what you're involved with here.
是吗
Really?
那另一种后果是什么呢
What's the other version of this conversation?
就是你派雇佣兵杀我女儿吗
The one when you send in the hired help to murder my little girl?
还是打算亲自动手
Or you gonna man up and do it yourself?
随便你选
What's your preference?
我只问你一次
I'm going to ask you this once.
擎天柱在哪
Where is Optimus Prime?
-快走  -撤离这里
- Come on. - Let's get out of here.
马上行动  地下室
We're moving. Basement.
他们来了
They're here.
出去  都出去
Get out! All of you!
科学展览会结束了  小东西们
Science fair's over, meatbags!
-毁掉实验室  -让开让开
- Destroy the lab! - Move, move, move, move!
小心  小心
Look out! Look out!
全部毁掉
Destroy it all!
危险  入侵  危险
Danger! Security breach! Danger...
各位  是我啊
Guys! It's me!
快把我救出这个折磨人的盒子
Break me out of this Frankenstein box!
住手
Stop!
那是我公司的财产
That's company property!
他们不是你的财产
They're not your property!
他们是我的朋友
They were my friends.
你现在怎么没话说了
Oh, you ain't talking so much now!
因为面前站着的探长吗
You got Hound in front of you, huh?
动手吧
Go ahead.
让我们都看清楚你们的为人
Show us your true colors, once and for all.
你一句话我就拍扁他
Just give me the word, I'll splatter him.
不如你告诉这个急脾气
Why don't you tell itchy fingers here
这些都是战争遗物  废铁而已
that this is all the spoils of war. Dead metal.
创新  我们是在研究科学
Innovation. What we do here is science.
就算我们不做  也有别人会做
Because if we don't do it, somebody else will.
因为你无法阻挡科技的脚步
Because you cannot stop technology!
我们不是供你们研究的科技
We're not your technology!
让我结果他吧
Let me vaporize his ass.
我破解了密码
I broke the code.
我掌握了你们的整个基因序列
I own your whole genome.
世界会知道你做了什么
The world will know what you're doing here.
世界  世界会认同我
The world? The world will approve.
我们可以创造你们了
We can make you now.
你还不明白吗  我们不再需要你们了
Don't you get it? We don't need you anymore.
这话真伤人
That was cruel.
汽车人
Autobots,
我们走
we're done.
这就走人  我们不教训教训他吗
We're done? We're not gonna kick a little bit of ass?
我早就想开杀戒了
I've been itching to kill something lately.
这是我们的机会  我们必须阻止他
This is our chance. We have to stop him.
你必须阻止他
You have to stop him.
它还没有实地测试过呢
It's never been tested in the field.
实验室和军事基地是有测试过
Labs, military bases,
但是还没有上过民用街道
but not on civilian streets.
就在下面  国防部合同内的财产
Down there a defense department contract
刚刚遭受了恐怖分子袭击
was just attacked in a terrorist attack.
现在归中情局管了
This is now a CIA military op.
你会获赔的  回答
You're indemnified. Respond!
走吧
Let's go.
芝加哥KSI  接入最近的卫星
Ksi Chicago, closest live sat, patch it in.
刚发生了一起汽车人袭击事件
Been an unprovoked autobot attack.
启动惊破天
Bring up Galvatron.
惊破天正在变形
Transforming Galvatron.
惊破天正在链接
Galvatron coming online.
启动毒刺
Bring up Stinger.
毒刺正在链接
Stinger coming online.
给那些外星恐怖分子看看
Let's show these alien terrorists
什么才叫升级
what an upgrade looks like.
惊破天和毒刺正在拦截目标
Galvatron and Stinger are moving to intercept targets.
收割者  五个可见目标  视野清晰
Reapers. Five targets in the open. Good picture.
三公里后拦截
Two Miles to intercept.
还有两百米
200 meters.
与目标相遇
Engage.
变形
Transform.
这是我们控制的  对吧
We are programming this, right?
是的  大部分吧
Yes. Mostly.
系统好像出现了故障
Systems seem to have malfunctioned.
瞄准五个目标
Targeting five bogeys.
准备火箭
Engaging rockets.
导弹发射
Missiles away.
快跑  大黄蜂  快
Gotta haul ass, Bee! Come on!
毒刺在追赶目标中
Stinger is in pursuit.
误开火  误开火
Misfire, misfire! Misfire, misfire!
系统故障  惊破天发射了4枚火箭
System failure. Galvatron just fired four rockets.
他们朝我们开火了
Whoa! They're shooting at us!
小心  你干什么呢
Watch out! What are you doing?
那是什么呀
What was that?
我们需要医疗小队  很可能有平民伤亡
We need a full medical team now. Possible civilian casualties.
现在火线上
I mean, you got a lot of
有许多平民  我不希望
people in the crossfire here. I don't like...
你正在创造历史
You're making history here.
为了你的祖国  为了世界
For your country, for the world.
人类的自由悬于一线
Human freedom is at stake.
时时刻刻都有无辜的人在死亡
Innocent people die all the time.
加油啊  擎天柱
Come on, Optimus!
泰莎
Tessa!
让他战斗  不要停
Make him fight. Don't let him go down.
让他战斗
Make him fight!
快快快
Come on, come on. Come on, come on.
泰莎
Tessa!
泰莎  向草坪跑
Tessa, run to the field!
你没有灵魂
You have no soul!
所以我才无所畏惧
That is why I have no fear!
死吧
You die!
救救我
Help me!
那是什么
What is that?
那是我的人  叫惊破天回来吧
That's my asset. Pull Galvatron back.
照办
Do it.
我得过去救她
I got to go get her.
泰莎
Tessa!
别出去  他会杀了你的
Don't go out there! He'll kill you!
-她需要我  -她躲起来了
- She needs my help! - She's hidden!
擎天柱  擎天柱  起来  快起来
Optimus! Optimus, get up, get up!
我做不到  快离开这儿
I can't. Get out of here.
我真是为你遗憾  擎天柱
I feel sorry for you, Prime.
因为你要效忠人类
Your allegiance to these humans.
要忠诚于某事的问题就在于
The trouble with loyalty to a cause is that the cause
到头来它一定会背叛你
will always betray you.
是谁派你来的
Who sent you here?
你以为你是从哪来的
Where do you think you came from?
你以为你是生下来的吗
You think you were born?
不  你是被制造出来的
No. You were built.
现在你的创造者要收回你
And your Creators want you back.
我们都在为别人工作
We all work for someone.
不要不要
No, no.
糟糕
No.
它抓住了她
It's got her!
-她在车里  -泰莎
- She's in the car! - Tessa!
-不要  -泰莎
- No! - Tessa!
爸爸
Dad!
泰莎  快出来
Tessa, get out!
快出来
Get out!
泰莎
Tessa!
快出来  泰莎
Get out! Tessa!
爸爸  救救我
Dad, help me!
-泰莎  -救救我  爸爸
- Tessa! - Help me, help me! Dad! Dad!
爸爸
Dad!
-爸爸  -泰莎  打碎玻璃
- Dad! - Tessa! Break the glass!
-打碎玻璃出来  -我在努力
- Break the glass to get out! - I'm trying!
-泰莎  我要掉下去了  -爸
- Tessa, I can't hold on! - Dad!
泰莎
Tessa!
-救救我  -打碎玻璃  打碎玻璃
- Help me! - Just break it! Break the glass!
泰莎
Tess...
凯德  快去提醒其他汽车人
Cade, warn the autobots!
爸爸  救救我  别丢下我
Dad, help me! Don't leave me!
不
No!
把那人类扔进垃圾堆
Take that human to the trash.
部长先生
Mr. Secretary.
我的人正在路上  这是中情局行动
My team is on the way. This is a CIA operation.
飞船是我的人
This is my asset.
让军队暂时待命
Tell the military to stand down.
稍等  白宫的电话
Hang on, I have the White House.
特工您好啊
Agent, hello!
哎呀呀我的天
Oh, my goodness. Boy,
这会儿全白宫上下可谓是群情激昂
is it a flurry of excitement over here at the White House.
大家都恨不能生吞了我
Everybody is super, super mad. At me.
我又看了一遍咱们上次的会议记录
So, I went over my notes from our last meeting,
貌似没有哪条记录中提到您说
and I'm not sure when you said anything about
"密歇根大道上空将出现巨型外星战舰"
"a giant alien warship over Michigan Avenue."
告诉总统  这不是袭击
Tell the President this is not an attack.
记得这艘船吗  擎天柱
Remember this ship, Prime?
就是你们这些骑士  战士建造的
Built for all you knights, you great crusaders,
以便你们探索宇宙
to explore the universe.
我霸占了它  它现在是我的私人监狱了
Well, I commandeered it. It's my personal prison now.
擎天柱
Optimus?
欢迎回到骑士圣域  擎天柱
Welcome back to the knights' temenos, Prime.
你让它蒙羞了
You have disgraced it.
和其他叛徒待一起吧  亡命垃圾
Join your fellow rebels, fugitive scum.
这里都是稀有物种
It's for the rarest of specimens.
是恶中至恶
The worst of the worst.
虽然花了几个世纪
It's taken centuries,
但除你以外的所有骑士都落入了我手中
but I've collected all the knights but you.
创造者想洗牌重来
The Creators want to sweep their chessboard clean.
我不是任何人的奴隶
I'm slave to no one.
各个物种互相干预
All this species mixing with species.
破坏了宇宙平衡
It upsets the cosmic balance.
创造者不希望这样
The Creators, they don't like it.
所以才造了你以供差遣
They built you to do what you were told.
那飞船怎么还没飞走
Why hasn't it taken off yet?
再快点  大黄蜂  它在下降
Come on, Bee, it's descending.
我们得上去
You got to get on it!
萨沃伊  任务完成
Savoy, mission accomplished.
禁闭抓住了擎天柱  可以完成交易了
Lockdown has Prime. The deal's going down now.
正在前往交接点取回种子
Picking up the seed at the recon point.
老巢  我是泰隆  降落点安全
Nest, Talon. L.Z. appears clear.
虽然我很享受这次猎捕
Much as I've enjoyed the hunt,
但我巴不得赶紧离开你们这破星球
I won't miss your wretched planet.
我们的交易到此为止
Our deal is done.
擎天柱换种子
One Prime for one seed.
小心使用
Handle it with care.
相信你们的种族已经准备好了
I trust your species is ready.
我们的种族不劳你费心
Don't worry about our species.
再会了  地球
Farewell, Earth.
快点  快点
Come on, come on!
大黄蜂  快
Bee, come on!
这是个坏主意  但我就喜欢坏主意
It's a bad idea. But I'm all about bad ideas.
上吧
Let's go!
好好玩两把
Well, let's rock.
这太疯狂了
This is crazy.
你要是想走  那最好现在快走
Look, you wanna cut and run, you better do it now.
我死也不会放弃
I'm gonna die trying.
听着  不是我帮你救女儿
Hey, I'm not here to help you get your daughter.
而是你帮我救女友
You're here to help me get my girlfriend.
启动暗物质引擎  全速前进
Engage dark-matter drives. Full power.
我们现在深入敌后了
We're behind enemy lines now.
禁闭的船到处是陷阱
Lockdown's ship has booby traps.
谨慎行事
Eyes open.
还得当心碎骨机  拌脑器  剥皮爪
Beware of his bone grinders, brain blinders, flesh peelers,
基因变异器
chromosomal inverters,
致瘫毒泥  黑洞暗门
catatonic sludge, black hole trapdoors,
当然还有  辐射
and, of course, radiation.
一定要快  出其不意
We must be quick. We have the element of surprise.
除非必要  不得动武
Let's try to use violence as a last resort.
啊  看刀
Oh, get it!
死  死去吧
I kill you! Kill you!
这些玩意儿真恶心
Ugh. I hate those things.
真诡异
That's freaky.
已经死了
He's not alive anymore.
寻找完毕  没找着  咱们撤吧
Well, we looked. They're not here. Let's go.
什么  没找到泰莎我哪都不去
What? Hey, I'm not going anywhere without Tessa.
我不懂  有我什么好处
I'm unclear. What's in it for me?
有你什么好处
What's in it for you?
悠着点  有话好好说
Easy. Let's use words.
好处就是我不会宰了你
What's in it for you is I don't kill you.
老大非救出来不可
We're getting the boss back.
还有那姑娘  懂了吗
And the girl. Copy?
好的好的  很有说服力  您真英雄
Okay, okay. Very persuasive. Textbook machismo.
那好  咱们得搞点破坏
Well, then. We'll need to sabotage something.
要快  因为暗物质引擎
Better hurry. Because dark-matter drives
正要启动
are preparing to take off.
真好
Oh, wonderful.
我预计还剩十分钟
I give us 10 minutes.
这就是引擎声  引擎在启动吗
Is that what that sound is? The engines filling up?
你的意思是这玩意儿
Are you telling me that thing's gonna be...
这玩意儿还有十分钟就要飞出地球了吗
It's gonna be flying out of here in 10 minutes?
-对头  -才十分钟吗
- Uh-huh. - Ten minutes?
没准九分钟  最快七分钟
Could be nine. Worst case, seven.
人类  去搜监禁区
Humans, search the cell blocks.
别废话了  咱们走
We're wasting time, let's go.
我们去找操控中枢
We'll find the center core.
行动
Let's move.
我们得让这破船停下来
We're gonna stop this nightmare ship.
这么大的船去哪找啊
We're never gonna find her in this huge ship.
简直是大海捞针
Like a needle in a haystack.
泰莎
Tessa!
好  很好
Great. Great.
干得漂亮
Oh, that was smooth.
你这招太高明了
No, that was really smooth,
这下全船都知道我们上船了
letting everybody know we're here.
这下有人要来搜捕我们了
Now they're gonna be looking for us.
快点  准星
Better hurry, Crosshairs,
否则这飞船就要飞进太空了
before we go into space!
原来这小东西在这呢
Ah. Here's the little jujube right here.
成功啦
Hello, mama.
谁抛的锚
Who fired the anchors?
谁在我船上捣鬼  有人越狱了
Who's on my ship? We have a loose prisoner.
快
Hurry up.
还剩六分钟了
We got like six minutes.
会找到她的
We'll find her.
慢着
Hold up.
快撤
Back up.
快  它们要发现我们了  藏起来
Come on, these things are gonna find us. Hurry, hide.
是武器
Weapons!
来搭把手  快点快点
Come here. Help me. Hurry, hurry.
托我上去
Help me up.
那边动静不太对头
There are some weird sounds out there.
-什么声音  -我不知道
- What is that? - I don't know.
准备好了吗
You ready?
冲
Run.
走之前一定要打一仗
All right, we're not going down without a fight.
等他们拐弯  我们打掉他们
They turn that corner, and we're gonna take them.
你废话说完了没
You ready or you gonna bitch out on me?
说完了  我保护你
No, I got your back.
-准备好了  -绝对的
- Are you ready? - Absolutely.
你可别说大话  真准备好了
Don't bitch out on me. Are you ready?
好了好了
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
我投降  我投降  我投降
Whoa, okay! I surrender! I surrender! I surrender!
抱歉  我太抱歉了
I'm so sorry! I'm so, so, so sorry!
你怎么做到的  怎么开的枪
What'd you do? How'd you do that?
我怎么知道
I have no idea!
你个糊不上墙的烂泥
You no-good, chickenshit little rat!
瞧瞧  你看见了吗
Look at that. You see that? Oh!
给我待在这儿  小可爱
You stay here, lucky charms!
我的天  我得赶紧抢注专利去
Oh, man. I am so gonna patent this shit.
泰莎
Tess!
爸  救我
Dad! Help me!
-泰莎  -泰莎
- Tess? - Tess!
快  快点
Come on, move, move!
泰莎
Tessa!
肖恩我爱死你了  你救了我
Shane, I love you! I love you! You saved me! You saved me!
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
谢谢  太谢谢你了
Thank you. Thank you so much.
谢谢  你救了我
Thank you. You saved me.
是啊  他救的你
Oh, yeah, he saved you. Yeah.
我看你需要和"投降"先生
I think you and Mr. "I surrender"
好好谈谈了  宝贝
have a lot to catch up about, sweetie.
他也救了我  你真该看看他有多拉风
He saved me, too. You should have seen him in there.
真是大英雄  咱们快走
I mean, our hero. Let's go. Now.
当心点
Eyes open.
马上就好
I almost got it.
大块头借过  闪开闪开
Big boy coming through! Move, move, move.
这肯定是超级监狱了
This has got to be the supermax.
当心转角
Watch the corners.
好多牢笼
There's a lot of cages.
是啊  一屋子怪物可怜虫
Oh, yeah. Creepy critters in here.
我可不想知道那大笼子里关的是什么
I don't want to know what's in the big cage.
这是什么
What's this?
猎狗  别多事
Hound, don't do it.
看起来没什么危险嘛
Aw, you don't look very dangerous in there.
真是丑出境界了
Oh, that's festering ugliness.
我被击中  我负伤了  我的脸要化了
I'm hit! I'm down! It's melting!
好疼
It burns!
我觉着是强酸
Ugh, I think it's acid!
见鬼  就是口水啊
Ah, nuts. It's just shizzle.
但愿不传染
I hope that's not contagious.
我要弄死你
I got to hurt you now.
你活着就讨人嫌
You're just too disturbing to live.
来一发  混蛋
Take that, bitch!
哈  你死翘翘了
Oh! You're dead.
-猎狗  -他还活着
- Hound! - He's alive!
撑住了老大  我们来救你了
Hold on, boss, we're coming!
-擎天柱  出个声  -这儿呢  快
- Optimus, sound off! - In here, quick!
坚持住  我们来了
Hang on, we're coming for you!
飞船侧翼有逃生舱
The arms of this knight ship detach!
我们可以从主舰分离  那是单独的
We can break free! It's a separate ship!
快
Hurry!
驾驶座在哪  左边右边
Where's the cockpit? Right or left?
-右边  -交给我了老大
- Right! - I'm on it, boss.
快  没时间了
Hurry. We have no time.
是  先生
Sensei.
来吧  这船我老早就想开一开了
Let's rock! I always wanted to fly one of these things.
我准备好了  老大
I'm there, boss!
大发明家耶格
Hey, Yeager technologies,
要不你来发明出条冲出去的路吧
you gonna invent us a way out of this one?
天哪
Oh, my God.
我不走这个
I am not doing this.
-我不走这个  -必须走
- I am not doing that. - Yes, we are.
没事  能站稳  来吧
No, it's good. It's stable. Come on.
不要
No way.
宝贝  知道我为什么来吗
Sweetie, you know why I'm here?
就是为了保护你
I'm here to protect you.
我觉得特安全
You've done great at that.
现在你要相信我  我们能下去  来吧
I want you to trust me right now. We're getting down. Let's go.
别往下看  好吗
Don't look down, okay?
朝前走  看  很简单的  别怕
Step. See, it's easy. Come on.
小心  缆线从这里开始变稀了
Careful, these cables are starting to get thinner here!
往前走  没错
Step. Step. There.
我的天
Oh, my God!
别往下看好吗  千万别看
See, don't look down! All right? Don't look down.
我们马上就到那边的大楼了
We're gonna be at the building in no time!
泰莎  你还好吗
You okay, Tess?
一直朝前走
Keep stepping.
天哪  天哪  爸爸
Oh, my God! Oh, my God, Dad! Oh!
宝贝  别停下来  好吗
All right, sweetie. You need to keep moving here, okay?
-来  -我不敢
- Come on! - I can't.
我害怕
I'm freaking out.
你必须朝前走
You need to move now!
我不干了  我要回到船上去
I'm not moving! I'm going back to the ship!
你不能回去  亲爱的
You can't go back to the ship, honey!
你看我能不能
Watch me!
你还没满18岁
You are not 18 years old yet
必须按我说的做  快和我们走
and you're gonna do what I say! Now let's go!
我们得朝前走  别回去好吗
We need to go this way, okay. Not that way.
罗密欧  管管她  快
Talk to her, Romeo! Now!
听你爸的  勇敢点
Come on, for God's sake.
别跟着掺和
Do not start with me.
天哪  怎么了
Oh, my God, what is that?
听我说  泰莎
All right, Tessa.
别回头看
Don't look back.
别这样说  这样我更想回头看了
Well, don't say that to me. Now I want to turn around.
亲爱的  没什么
It's nothing major, sweetie.
你这么说绝对是有什么
Well, that means it's totally major!
我的枪可能要指向你那边
I have to point this gun in your direction.
你以为是指着你  其实不是
It's gonna feel like it's in your direction, but I'm not.
-动作快点  -你要害死我吗
- You better hurry. - Are you trying to kill me?
我可是拼了老命才混上这条船的
I had to bust my ass to get up here on this spaceship!
-开枪  -给我趴下
- Shoot it! - Get down now!
泰莎等在那
Tessa, wait!
我来接你  泰莎
I'm coming for you! Tessa! Oh!
-我的天  -我来了
- Oh, my God! - I'm coming!
抓紧
Hold on!
大黄蜂  你最赞  你最赞
You're the best, bee! You are the best.
没错  记住我是最棒的
You damn right! And don't ever forget it.
看看  我们终于从船上出来了
You see that? Look at me! We're off the ship, right?
大黄蜂  大黄蜂  自己人
Bumblebee! Bumblebee! Friendly!
敌舰要追上来了  赶紧上来
Enemy ships are coming in hot. Get on! Get on!
坐稳了  我可要开打了
Hold your knickers, I'm punching it!
那来了三艘飞船
They got three ships on them!
我来陪它们玩玩水
I'm giving it the juice!
大黄蜂  干掉它们
Come on, bee, take them out!
大黄蜂  干的漂亮
Good move, bee!
混蛋  尝尝这个
This one's for you, a-holes!
还有什么招快拿出来
If you're gonna do something, you better do it!
来吧
Come on!
我看不下去了  你来开  我来打
I'm sick of this crap. You fly. I shoot.
要不让我来打
Hey, you better let me fire this big-ass gun
我们好飞得快点
and make this ship go faster!
听好了  教你们速成  这是追踪枪
Listen up! Crash course. Tracer guns.
往前推是开火  往回扳是装弹
Punch forward to fire, slide back to reload.
什么
What?
推端扳  重复  推端扳  重复
Punch, hold, slide, repeat. Punch, hold, slide, repeat.
等等  你在说什么
Wait. What're you talking about?
-我也没明白他的意思  -祝好运
- I don't know what he means. - Good luck.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我去解恨
To lay some hate.
-说一遍  -好
- Say it! - Okay.
推  端  扳  重复
Punch, hold, slide, repeat.
冲啊
Go!
太爽了  打中了一架
Yeah, I got one! Whoo!
这外星玩意真带劲
These alien guns kick ass!
快点  要追上来了
Come on, he's on us!
大黄蜂  甩掉它  低头
Bee, you gotta move! Duck!
大黄蜂  开枪
Bee, fire the gun!
不好
Uh-oh!
太刺激了
That was insane!
泰莎你还好吧
Tess, you okay?
好吧  先生
Okay. Sir?
你最好上了保险
You better have insurance!
上保险
Insurance?
这他妈可是宇宙飞船
It's a freaking spaceship.
你给宇宙飞船上个保险试试
You go get insurance on a freaking spaceship.
祝你好运  哥们儿
Good luck with that, buddy!
这是你的车
Is this your car? Huh?
宝贝  把我的外星枪拿来
Sweetie, hand me my alien gun.
给
Here you go.
当心
Come here.
-相信你老爸没错  -好的
- Trust your dad. - Okay.
准备星际旅行
Prepare for interstellar launch.
就快和母船分离了  马上就好
We're almost ready to separate. We're almost there.
快  它要发动了
Hurry, he's launching!
包在我身上  老大
All over it, chief.
禁闭得跑很远才能发现我们跑掉了
Lockdown will be in deep space before he realizes I'm gone.
我飞行技术很烂
I'm a sucky pilot,
不过还是试试吧
but let's give it a whirl.
好嘞
Hell, yeah!
你们中情局真是低调
You CIA guys are really subtle.
手法利落  一定不会有人注意到
What a deft hand. I'm sure nobody noticed all that.
听着  过几分钟警察就要来了
Look. In a few minutes, there are gonna be feds
而且得有好多  我不希望他们
all over this place, and I don't want them
发现我们的宝贝
finding our holy grail.
所以我们要把整个研发机构
So we're gonna take all our R&D,
都转移到中国的工厂去  没错
we're moving it to our China facility. Yeah.
我要你把种子带给我
I want you to bring me the seed,
不过是带到中国再给我
but I want you to bring it to me there.
乔舒亚先生  我觉得
Mr. Joshua, I would not describe
你产品的测试结果好像不算理想
your product testing as perfected.
到了中国我们有足够的时间改进
We have plenty of time for improvements in China.
先生  惊破天他简直是
Sir, Galvatron. He was...
惨败
A fiasco.
是四不像  是耻辱
A farrago. An embarrassment.
它还会说话  这又是怎么搞的
And he spoke. How did that happen?
温布利  你知道瑕疵意味着什么吗  瑕疵
Do you know what a flaw is, Wembley? A flaw?
瑕疵等于彻底失败
A flaw is a total failure.
我无法完全控制我的产品
I did not have control over my prototype,
我想知道为什么
and I want to know why!
我们把好消息告诉大黄蜂吧
Let's give Bumblebee the good news.
我们弄到船了  可以离开了
We got a ship now. We're leaving.
你们人类  我们为你们做了这么多
You humans. After all we have done.
你们却自取灭亡
You don't know what you've wrought upon yourselves.
什么  又怎么了
What? What is it now?
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我已经尽力了啊
I mean, I'm doing stuff out of my league here!
你们没搞清楚到底是谁在操控谁
You don't see who's controlling who.
和那个人造金刚交手时
Within that manmade prototype I fought,
我感受到了威震天
I sensed the presence of Megatron.
什么  引发芝加哥之战的那个霸天虎
What, the Decepticon that started the Chicago war?
那你以为KSI
How do you think KSI
是怎么造机器人的
built those bots in the first place, hmm?
他们有很多
They had a whole mess of
废掉的霸天虎脑袋  下载它们大脑的数据
dead decepticon heads and they were downloading their minds!
我就负责尸检
And I was in charge of autopsy duty.
没有工会  没有福利  什么都没有
No union, no benefits, no nothing.
他们把我连到威震天上
They hooked me up to Megatron,
可它的大脑根本没有死透
and that mind wasn't as dead as they thought.
是它为他们提供了技术和数据
He fed them the science and specs!
就为了让他们给它造一个新身体
All so they could build him a brand-new body.
威震天则把他的意识复制进去
Then he infected it with his evil, nasty chromosomes.
那些红眼珠子的东西
They had red, beady eyes.
弄的我身上到处都是
They got all in my lovely locks.
我现在还能闻到味道
Oh, I can smell it right now.
那是不折不扣的量身定制
Total inside custom job!
尽管KSI给它起了个
KSI might have named the body
威风的名字惊破天
the snappy name of Galvatron,
但那不过是威震天的转世
but that's just Megatron reincarnated!
你明知道这些却没有提醒他们
You knew this and you didn't warn them?
小姑娘  在死囚牢房时
Little girl, you can go to a pretty dark place
会变得无比阴暗
when you on death row.
他把KSI玩弄于股掌
He's been playing KSI all this time,
就为了操控他们
all so that he could manipulate them
让他们设法得到种子
into going after the seed.
等等  种子
Wait. The seed?
那些追杀我们的士兵
Those nasty soldiers that were chasing us.
我看到他们登船  拿走了什么东西
I saw them board the ship, and they took something
应该是种子
that they called the seed.
听着  大约在六千万年前
Listen. Sixty million years ago,
误差可能不小
give or take an eon...
数千颗行星通过种子被赛博坦化
Thousands of planets were cyber-formed with seeds.
它们会将你们的有机世界
They turned your organic life
变成我们所需的基本金属元素
into our elemental metals.
我们的祖先为了创造我们
Our creators destroyed your world
毁灭了你们的世界
to make us.
这也是惊破天要做的事
And that's what Galvatron wants to happen again.
它想在最大的城市
He wants to detonate that seed
引爆种子  消灭百万人类
in the biggest city and kill millions!
它要以这种方式向世界宣告它的华丽回归
He's gonna show the world, "Baby, I'm back."
爆炸波会把整个城市烧成个金属熔炉
The blast wave will incinerate that city into molten metal.
它将拥有足够的资源组建一支庞大的军队
He'll have enough to build a massive army
然后把你们人类消灭干净
and annihilate your species forever.
你们这群愚蠢贪婪的混蛋
You dumb, greedy bastards
完全是自掘坟墓
just brought extinction to yourself.
反正也不关我的事  我总算是自由了
Not my problem though, I'm free at last.
这对我来说可是好事  我要走了
Whole thing worked out good for me. I'm walking.
我们得在惊破天之前找到种子
We got to get the seed before Galvatron does.
中国  北京
种子将是拯救公司的关键
The seed is going to be the salvation of our company.
我们今晚就运送
We take delivery tonight.
下个月  我们将在蒙古沙漠
And next month, we detonate safely
安全引爆
in the Mongolian desert.
我们制造的变形元素
And we'll create enough transformium
够使用一百年
for a hundred years.
老爸  我不想再逃亡和偷窃了
Dad, I'm tired of running and stealing.
有地方睡觉了
Well, a place to sleep.
紧接着就又干一票闯空门
Yeah. Just another break-in.
我在你这个年纪时
You know, when I was your age,
喜欢来点放纵  喜欢香车美女
I liked to get a little wild. I liked cars, girls.
然后就有了泰莎
But then there was Tessa.
她出生后  我心里只剩下了
And when she was born, all I ever wanted out of life
她的快乐  健康  安全
was for her to be happy and healthy and safe.
我总以为有我保护她就够了
Somehow I thought I'd always be enough to protect her.
但并非如此
But I won't be.
从来不是如此
I'll never be.
所以我希望有人能做到
So somebody better be.
谢谢你和我们共度难关  小可爱
Thanks for being here today, lucky charms.
我也谢谢你没趁机宰了我
Well, thanks for not shooting me when you had the chance.
以后机会多着呢
Oh, I'll have more.
可不是吗
Yeah, I can see that.
我们刚刚拦截了一通密报
We've intercepted the encrypted communications.
乔舒亚·乔伊斯正赶往他中国广州的工厂
Joshua Joyce is headed to his factory in Guangzhou, China.
听着  大老板
Hey, big shot.
你的公司麻烦大了
Your company's in serious trouble.
你最好确保你有个好律师
You better have a damn good lawyer.
是吗  我看该找律师的是你
Really? Well, you better have a great one
这城市将被夷为平地  而这都是因为你
'cause you're about to be responsible for the annihilation of a city.
你现在给我听着
Now you listen to me.
你的技术被黑  产品被感染
Your tech has been hacked. Your prototypes are infected.
惊破天已经开始在找那枚种子了
And now galvatron is after that seed.
我知道你良心未泯
Look. I know you have a conscience
因为你我一样  都是发明家
because you're an inventor, like me.
千万不要让惊破天接近种子
Do not let Galvatron anywhere near that seed.
惊破天受我控制  我制造了他
I control Galvatron. I created him.
我想你心里其实很清楚
Deep down, I know you know.
一直都是他在操纵你
Your prototype's been controlling you.
坐这玩意儿绕地球半圈快吗
How fast can that thing get us halfway around the world?
非常快
Very.
这可是宇宙飞船
It's a spaceship.
要想一起走  现在就得上路了
If we're traveling, now's the time.
我只是想让生活恢复平静
All I want is to have our life back.
去还是留  取决于你自己
It's your call. Whatever you want.
是靠自己更安全  还是和他们在一起呢
Are we safer on our own, or are we safer with them?
她是个值得珍惜的宝贝
She's a keeper.
大概是随了她妈妈吧
Must take after her mom.
这次还真让你说对了
I can't argue with that, kid.
走吧  我们去把种子夺回来
Move! We're retrieving the seed,
但以后我们也不必再保护人类了
but then we're done defending the humans.
什么  不必
What, done?
什么意思  什么叫不必了
What do you mean, you're done?
意思就是拜拜再见永别了
Means "Finished," "See ya," "Good-bye."
劫走了飞船的一部分
Hijacked part of my ship?
你们都是干什么吃的
How did you let this happen?
给我关掉暗物质引擎  掉转航线
Shut down dark-matter drive, reverse course at light speed,
火速返回地球
and get us back!
擎天柱抢走了我的战利品展柜
Prime's taken my trophy case.
我一定会让他死的很难看
And he will feel my wrath!
KSI 中国区工厂
欢迎来到中国
Welcome to China.
隔离惊破天  告诉工程师
Put Galvatron in containment. Tell the techs
不要启动它
do not activate him.
好的  先生
Absolutely, sir.
乔伊斯
Joyce.
我都快等不及把这玩意儿给你了
I cannot tell you how enthused I am to deliver this.
外星礼物清单上的第一名吧
Top of your alien wish list.
它是你的了  或者说
It's yours. Or rather...
是我们的了
ours.
我想先看看我的预付款
I will need to see my advance.
500万公司股份
Five million shares of the company.
我们联手将结束人类战争
Together, we're gonna end human warfare.
一支全自动化军队将代替人类出战
We're about to build a fully automated U.S. Army.
想想我们能挽救多少美国人的生命
Just think of all the American lives we're gonna save.
什么时候可以开始批量生产
So how soon until we can start continuous production?
我看这件事不如缓缓吧
You know, why don't we take a beat on this for a minute?
我刚发现了一些新数据  而且...
I have some new data that I discovered and...
你不会是要反悔吧
You're not backing out on me here?
不  怎么会  我只是...
No, I'm not backing out. I just...
我当然想要种子
I want the seed.
没说我不想要它
I'm not saying I don't want the seed.
我只是不知道是不是....
I'm just saying I don't know if I...
是不是我现在就需要它
if I want the seed right now.
你知道牺牲了多少精英拿到了它吗
Good men have died trying to get that thing for us.
是为你
For you.
我当然知道你做了些什么
I know what you did to get that thing.
全是些见不得人的非法勾当
A lot of illegal, icky shit.
我可以分分钟让你下台  黑色行动先生
I can take you down, too, Mr. Black ops.
最好不要威胁我
Don't you threaten me.
年少时我就创立了这家公司
I started this company when I was a boy,
梦想着让这个世界更和平美好
with a dream of making the world a better place.
有意思  我的梦和你的一样
Funny. I had the same dream.
可你却一路顺风顺水  几百万信手拈来
Somewhere along the way, you made billions of dollars.
所以麻烦你告诉我我的梦还缺点什么
So why don't you tell me what's missing from my dream?
我儿时的梦想怎么就
Why don't you tell me what's missing
这么打水漂了
from my boyhood dream?
我为国家效力了几十年
I have served my country for decades
才得到了空前的盛世
of unparalleled prosperity
你现在可是我手里的金钥匙
and you are my golden parachute.
有什么好处的话  休想丢下我
So you are damn well jumping out of the plane with me!
惊破天在此
I am Galvatron!
出什么事儿了
What's going on?
你那心爱的惊破天自己启动了
Your Galvatron has gone active.
你到底对我隐瞒了什么
What haven't you been telling me?
去找达西  叫一辆车在楼下候着
Find Darcy, and bring a car around downstairs.
动静小点儿
Quietly.
刚刚出了点小状况
We got a factory emergency.
我得带你离开这里
I have to get you out of here.
-什么情况  -带他们离开
- What the hell's going on? - Take them outside.
我们可是说好了的  你得到你想要的了
We had a deal. You've got what you wanted.
是"它"想要的
I got what "It" wanted.
我的兄弟们  今天你们将恢复自由之身
My brothers, today I grant you your freedom.
从现在起  你们得听从我的指挥
And from now on, you are commanded by me.
起来吧
Rise up!
给我把种子找回来
Go find my seed!
再去最大的城市把种子引爆
Detonate the seed in the largest city.
公主大人  我不想听你说什么
Listen, princess. I don't wanna hear,
"我早说过"
"I told you so,"
但这确实比我想象的要危险
but this is much more dangerous than I think.
快上车
Get in.
惊破天也黑了其他机器人
Galvatron's hacked into the others.
-什么  -乔舒亚
- What? - Joshua.
-你得管管这儿  -开车  开车
- You have to contain this! - Drive, drive!
你个混...
Son of a...
快点  跟上  跟上  动作麻利点
Come on. Let's move, let's move, let's move!
我知道怎么在香港甩掉他们
I know how to lose them in Hong Kong.
那儿有防御工程  应该能上帮大忙
I know a military garrison there that will help us.
威胁中情局的职业杀手
Threatening a professional CIA killer.
好像不怎么光彩
Possibly not my finest hour.
这句话要是能收回就好了
I'd like to have that one back.
杀手
Killer?
-我还以为你们是朋友  -不
- I thought they were your friends! - No,
不是朋友  商业伙伴罢了
No. Not friends. Business.
炸弹也是他们给的
They gave me this bomb.
-炸弹  -天哪
- Bomb? - Oh!
你是说袋子里有颗炸弹吗
Is that a bomb in the bag?
没错  袋子里是有颗炸弹
Yes, there's a bomb in the bag.
我去
Shit.
你之前说不必继续保护人类了
When you said you were done fighting for humans,
你不是认真的  对吧
you didn't mean that, did you?
我们到底还要牺牲多少
How many more of my kind must be sacrificed
来弥补你们犯下的过错
to atone for your mistakes?
你以为人类是完美的吗
Well, what do you think being human means?
人类就是这样
That's what we do.
人类会犯错误
We make mistakes.
但有时候正是这些错误
And sometimes out of those mistakes
带来了最棒的意外
come the most amazing things.
当初把你修好  只是为了拿赏金
When I fixed you, it was for a reward.
没别的  仅此而已  就是为了钱
That was it. That was why. For money.
这是我犯下的错误
And it was me making a mistake.
可若不是那一时贪念也就没有你了
Without it, you wouldn't be here.
所以不管你对我们有多失望
So even if you got no faith in us,
也请你和我一样
I'm asking you to do what I do.
试着从废墟里寻找珍宝
I'm asking you to look at all the junk and see the treasure.
你需要保持信念  擎天柱
You gotta have faith, prime,
相信我们拥有的可能性
in who we can be.
香港
钱就这么打水漂
I'm seriously pissed
真是不爽到家了
we're not getting paid for this.
至少可以享受掉除掉他的乐趣
Well, at least we get to kill him.
有了卫星追踪  看他们能跑哪儿去
They're not getting away if I still got him on satellite.
以为自己能逃出中情局的掌心  太有才
Some genius. Thinks he can outrun the CIA.
-乔舒亚  -怎么了
- Joshua? - Yes?
那炸弹的威力有多大
How lethal is that bomb?
不清楚  我问问
Uh, I don't know. Let me check.
太棒了  我爱死这个了
I love this! This is so good.
稍等
Oh, hang on.
老大在香港来信了
I'm getting a text from il duce in Hong Kong.
"给我查出这颗种子的爆炸范围"
"Need to know the seed's estimated blast range."
什么
Duh.
我来引开他们
I'll do the diversion!
把那玩意儿送到安全的地方去
Get that thing somewhere safe!
老兄  杀手就快来了  快点行吗
Killers are coming! Guys, we gotta go!
伙计们  老兄...
Guys, guys...
-给我闭嘴  -好吧好吧  对不起
- Shut up! Shut up! - All right! I'm sorry, All right!
你们继续  你们继续
Go ahead, go ahead!
-搞定了吗  -别别别  等一下
- Okay, good? - No, don't... don't go! Wait!
好了  他卖了
Okay, he's in.
好了吗  快走快走
Okay, okay, okay.
你得给我加薪  我要加薪
I need a raise! I want a raise.
行  行  行  你要什么都行
All right, yes! I'm sure whatever you want!
快快快
Go, go, go!
我去  不是吧
Oh, no!
我们死定了  我们死定了
Death is on our tail! Death is on our tail!
快闪开  你们这群人
Get out of the way, all of you!
别挡路中间
Get out of the way!
我可不想就这么挂了
I don't want to die like this.
围住他们
Box them in.
-别停  别停  快点  -来了
- Hurry, hurry! Come, come. - Okay, yes.
你去哪儿我跟哪儿  你简直太棒了
I'll follow you anywhere. You're amazing!
我得把你送到天台去
We're going to get you to the roof.
行  行  没问题
Good, good, good.
进去
Go!
像蘑菇云一样
哈哈
像蘑菇云一样哈哈
Like a tactical nuke.
像蘑菇云一样
哈哈
像蘑菇云一样哈哈
Like a tactical nuke.
"哈哈"  太搞笑
Lol. That's funny.
我简直  这是真的假的啊
I can't... This is really happening.
我一个身价百亿的大亨  竟然...
A man, me, who is worth over 20 billion dollars is now...
竟然被中情局杀手追得满街跑  你信吗
being chased by CIA assassins. That's the truth.
先不说手下的机器人全部造反
And in the middle of a robot uprising.
我还带着一颗随时会爆炸的核弹
And I'm carrying what is, in essence, a tactical nuke.
这还不算什么...
And the great thing is I...
最棒的是我竟然
The great thing is that I'm...
竟然感觉不到时差的存在
I'm barely feeling any jetlag.
-闹够了没  -什么
- Just stop it! - What?
你得抓紧时间躲到天台上去
You need to hide on the roof of this building.
我叫直升机去救你
I'll get you a helicopter extraction.
好吧
Okay.
我挺喜欢她的
I like her.
多迷人的姑娘
I find her very attractive.
他一定在这儿附近
He's definitely around here.
求你了  快动啊
Come on, come on.
这儿有辆摩托
I got a bike!
过去检查一下
Check in there!
他们就是我说的中情局杀手
These are the CIA assassins I told you about.
-呃  伙计们  -给我走
- Whoa! Guys. - Let's go.
你们好啊
Hello.
住手
Hey!
好吧
Okay.
-捡起来  -好吧  我这就去
- Pick it up. - All right. I'm gonna.
老天
Wow.
天哪  太谢谢你了
Wow. Wow, thank you.
天哪  你又是怎么...
Wow! How did you...
警校训练  去商学院之前参加的
Police training, prior to my MBA.
我爱你
I love you.
快去天台
Get to the roof.
好吧  这就去
All right, okay.
种子就在这儿  给我找出来
Find my seed. It's here!
那些机器人一直在追踪那枚种子
Those prototypes are after that bomb.
不会吧
No!
别  别  别走
No, no, no, no!
上面是什么人
Who the hell's aboard that?
这不可能
Impossible.
弟兄们  是汽车人  击落它
Brothers, it's the autobots! Shoot them down!
乔舒亚
Joshua!
光头
Hey, baldy!
是我
Hey, it's me! Hey!
带上它  我们走
Bring it over now! Let's go.
快  快跑
Hurry up, run!
-快点  快  -我们走  离开这
- Hurry! Come on! - Let's go! Move it!
快过来  给我
Guys! Come on. Give it to me now!
看来有敌人来了
Looks like we might have company.
我们中弹了  中弹了
We're hit! We're hit!
要是留他们活口  我们就死定了
They live, they talk, we're dead.
格杀勿论
Kill them all.
乐意效劳
Pleasure.
下面有十个
I count ten below!
你不是说只有一个原型机被感染吗
I thought you said you had one prototype get infected.
他又控制了其他五十个
Now he's got operational control of my other 50.
我们走
Come on.
爬上去  爬上去
Climb, climb!
包围他们
Surround them.
虽然祸是我闯下的
I may have started the apocalypse,
但你把家人都扯进来了
but you brought your family.
家长做得太不称职
And that's, you know, terrible parenting.
再乱说我就揍你一顿
Oh, I'm about one second away from knocking you out,
带上炸弹  把你扔在这
taking the bomb, and just leaving you here.
那算是帮我大忙了
Please, do me a favor.
擎天柱  汽车人  还活着吗
Optimus, Autobots, you alive?
-去你的  混蛋  -快走
- Come on, bitch! - Come on!
撤退  撤退
Evac! Evac!
我们被夹击了
We're getting flanked!
下方还有
We got company below!
我的大屁股被卡住了  大黄蜂  射击
My fat ass is stuck! Bee, take the shot!
进电梯  进去
Into the elevator! Get in. Okay.
快点
Come on.
下去  下去
Get down, get down!
关门  关门
Close the door! Close the door!
还不走  怎么不关门
Won't go! It's not closing!
超重了
There's too much weight.
-下去找大黄蜂  -爸爸  别走
- Get back down to Bumblebee! - Dad, no!
冲我来
You want me!
中央电梯
Center elevator.
他会没事的
He's gonna be okay.
外星炸弹来了  外星炸弹来了
Alien bomb! Alien bomb, coming through!
快让开  让...  小朋友们好
Clear the way! Clear the... hi, kids.
快让开  女士们
Coming through, ladies!
借过  借过  女士们  借过
Excuse me! Excuse me, ladies! Excuse me!
天啊
Oh, my God!
快他妈的闪开用中文怎么说
How do you say, "Get the fuck out of the way" in Chinese?
这里可不低呢
That's a long way down.
真的假的啊
You've got to be kidding me.
不
No!
拜托
Come on.
我会抓到你的
I'm coming for you!
你当初真不该藏下那辆卡车
Never should have hidden that truck.
你真不该伤害我家人
You should have never came after my family.
算你不走运  我们都有家人
Tough luck, you're here. We all have family.
没错  但我会活着见到她们的
Yeah, but I'm gonna live to see mine.
我要抓的逃犯在哪
Where is my escaped bounty?
汽车人在这
Autobots at this location.
擎天柱在附近
Prime is close.
尽管下手吧
Do whatever you have to do.
正合我意
I intend to.
-达西  -乔舒亚
- Darcy! - Joshua!
那边过来三个
We got three more coming in from that way!
大黄蜂  泰莎呢
Bee, where's Tessa?
爸爸
Dad!
我们是陷入了困境了  好吗
We got a real dilemma here. Okay?
我创造的精密机器人
I created incredible robots.
都是为了打败变形金刚而设计的
It's all designed to kick that fat Transformer's ass.
所以我们真的必败无疑
So, really, this is a no-win situation.
没什么好说的
It's over.
这话好过分
That was mean.
你不能接受残酷的事实  我也没办法
Hey! I'm sorry if you can't handle the cold-hearted truth!
擎天柱  我可以怎么对待这些人类
Optimus, what are my orders with these humans?
可以捏扁那个光头吗
Can I squish the bald guy?
他们处境危险
They're in trouble.
这又不关我们的事
Nah! This isn't our fight!
给他们当炮灰  我受够了
I'm done being an underdog. Underdogs suck!
他们就该自作自受
I say they get what they deserve.
怎么办  擎天柱
What's the play, Prime?
该找点援军了
It's time for reinforcements.
听命于你的骑士吧
Recognize one of your knights.
传奇继续
The legend exists.
快走
Come on.
快跟上 跟上 我们走
All right, come on! Come on, let's go!
大黄蜂  快走
Bee, go!
快  离开这  离开这
Come on, we got to move! Let's go, move!
泰莎呢  泰莎过来  快
Where's Tessa? Tessa, get over here! Come on.
过来
Get over here!
躲在我身后  我掩护你们
Stay behind me! I'm covering you!
要是掩护没了  说明我死了
If I stop covering you, it means I'm dead.
不过那不可能
But that ain't gonna happen.
吃枪子吧
Take that!
我是个邪恶机器勇士
I'm a wicked warrior robot!
该死
Goddamn!
快  我们离开这
Come on! We gotta move now!
快跑  快跑
Go, go!
敌人从那边过来了
We got hostiles coming down the street!
快走
Go!
大黄蜂  十二点方向  火力掩护
Bee! Twelve o'clock! Cover fire!
我们被包围了
We're surrounded!
快跑  快跑  快跑
Hustle, hustle, hustle!
火箭
Rocket!
快  快  快
Go, go, go!
低下身
Get down!
真是个绝佳的藏身之处
Oh, this is the perfect place to hide.
大玻璃箱子
A big glass box!
生怕别人找不到
Nobody will ever find us here!
真是...
That's...
开玩笑呢吧
You've got to be kidding me.
传奇勇士们  当初创造我们的力量
Legendary warriors, the powers that created us
现在却要毁灭我们
now want us all extinguished.
我们必须团结一致  否则只会沦为奴隶
We must join forces, or else forever be their slaves.
今天不和我们并肩作战
So today you stand with us
就得与我为敌
or you stand against me.
让擎天柱自己搞定吧
We'll let Prime figure this one out.
明智
Very wise.
我才不愿意跟他们混在一起
There's no friggin' way I'm staying down here with them.
休想  没门
No way. No way.
只有团结一致  才能生存
Only together can we survive!
听从我的指挥
Let me lead you!
不是吧
Oh, no.
我还以为会变成大车呢
I was expecting a giant car.
来吧
Come here!
我们会带给你们自由
We're giving you freedom.
捍卫我的家人
You defend my family,
不然死路一条
or die.
汽车人
Autobots,
我们要证明自己
we're going to prove who we are
活出我们的价值
and why we're here!
怎么就是心甘情愿为他卖命呢
Ugh, you just want to die for the guy.
这是领导力  或者叫洗脑什么的
That's leadership. Or brainwashing, or something.
不  这就是擎天柱的魅力
No. That's Optimus Prime.
汽车人  我们一起进攻
Autobots, we charge together!
现在  进击
Now, roll out!
我们被围攻了  四面受敌
We're getting boxed in! We're getting flanked everywhere!
请求支援
Help me out here!
不留活口
Kill anything that moves!
快  凯德  开枪
Come on, Cade, shoot!
来受死吧  混蛋
Come and get some, you little bitch!
子弹来了
Incoming!
真不敢相信我把性命托付给你了
I can't believe I'm putting my life in your hands.
别客气  枪给你  你来拿着
Here, be my guest. Take the gun. Come on, take it.
不  我不想拿枪
No, I don't want the gun.
那就躲在下面  闭嘴
Then stay under there and shut up!
没问题
All right.
你用的好所以自己留着吧
You're good with the gun. So you keep it.
弹药不足了
Running out of guns and ammo.
来受死吧
Come and get some!
你们死期已到
You're all gonna die!
干得漂亮
Way to go, baby!
好枪法  凯德
Good shooting, Cade!
我就像个胖胖的芭蕾舞娘
I'm like a fat ballerina
但招招致命
who takes scalps and slits throats!
来吃一口幸运饼干
Got your fortune cookie!
滚开  臭小子
Come here, you little punk.
拉开安全栓  我要扛不住了
Pull the pin! I'm dying out here!
给你  给你
Here! Take it. Take it!
帮个忙  帮个忙
Little help! Little help!
触发了  触发了  快接着
It's live! It's live, it's live. Take it!
给我做什么
What do you want me to do with it?
-扔过去  -给我  给我
- Just throw it! - Give, give, give!
坏消息  凯德
Got some bad news, Cade.
我没有弹药  也无路可走了
I'm out of ammo and out of ideas.
再快些  冲
Faster! Go!
我要杀了你
I'll kill you!
冲啊
Charge!
这不可能
No, impossible!
他们把一切都搞砸了
They're ruining everything!
吃我一拳
Take that!
滚开
Get off me.
-站起来  猎狗  -我不行了
- Get up, hound! - I can't go on.
你要继续奋战
But you gotta keep fighting!
油箱空了  伙计
Tank's empty, bro.
敌人越来越多  如果你不继续奋战
There's more of 'em coming. If you don't get up
我们必死无疑  上啊
and fight, we're going to die. Let's go!
出击
Attack!
擎天柱在此
Optimus is here!
大黄蜂  跳上来
Bee, jump!
最讨厌廉价山寨货了
I hate cheap knockoffs.
干得漂亮
Awesome job!
-你  -你说谁
- You. - Who?
-你  -上前来
- You. - Step forward.
等等  干什么
Wait. Why?
人类的灭顶之灾都是你的科技带来的
Your science will be responsible for humanity's extinction.
好吧  我知道你对这个
All right. I know that you're sensitive
生物伦理困境很敏感
to this whole bioethical dilemma.
也许他只是想听你承认
Maybe all he wants to hear you say is
有些东西本不该被发明出来
that some things should never be invented.
好吧
Okay.
我们会带领你们出城
We'll lead you out of the city.
把种子安全带到山头去
Get that seed safely to the hills.
用这辆车
Use this car.
他差点吃了我
He almost ate me!
可以启动
All right, we're good!
出发吧
All right, let's go!
让出驾驶座
Get out of that seat.
你女儿碰到我算你走运
And you're one lucky dad to have me.
小可爱  我同意  你来开  出发
Okay, lucky charms. You got that. You drive. Let's go.
你干什么了
What did you do?
我不知道  但有麻烦了
I don't know. I don't know, but it's an issue.
-你按了什么键吗  -它要爆炸了吗
- Did you press a button? - Is it gonna blow up?
我不知道
I don't know.
这玩意儿响了  肯定是你按到什么了
This thing is beeping now, so you must have hit something.
-它要爆炸了吗  - 我不知道
- Is it gonna blow up? - I don't know!
一个炸弹在响  你不觉得不妙吗
A bomb starts beeping, that might signal a problem, you think?
我只是说它在很稳定地闪光
I'm just saying that it's a steady blinking light,
也许是个计时器
which could be a timer of some kind.
或者是定位信号
Unless it's signaling location.
给谁的信号
To who?
我们得向中央政府求助
We've got to call the central government for help!
擎天柱
Optimus prime.
回来吧
Come to me.
桥在那
There's the bridge.
倒车  倒车
Back it up! Back it up!
快快快  倒车  倒车
Go, go, go, go! Back up! Go back! Go back!
快  让开路  我看不到了
Move! Get out of the way. I can't see!
-肖恩  开快点  -镇定
- Shane, drive faster! - Okay, just calm down.
肖恩  小心
Shane, watch out!
-去找掩护  -倒车  倒倒倒
- Get cover! - Back up! Back! Back up!
汽车人  撤退
Autobots, fall back!
-躲开  给我让路  -让路
- Come on, move! Out of my way! - Get out of the way!
-小心  -撞吧  直接撞
- Look out! - Just hit them! Just hit them!
那是个大磁铁
It's a big magnet!
它会把金属吸上天  再丢下来
It's sucking up metal and dropping it!
-开快点  -让开路
- Go faster! Go faster! - Get out of the way!
它过来了  过来了
It's coming! It's coming!
它更近了
It's coming closer!
开快点  肖恩
Go faster, Shane!
-小心  -小心
- Watch out! - Look out!
它向我们转回来了  向右打方向
Oh, no, now it's circling back towards us! Hard right!
向右打方向
Take a hard right!
我的神啊
Oh, my God!
糟糕  是磁铁  下车
Oh, no. No, the magnet. Get out, get out!
快  快下车
Come on! Come here! Get out!
不不不  我们升起来了  抓住炸弹
No, no, no! No, we're going up. Grab the bomb!
帮我抓住炸弹
Help me grab the bomb!
我解不开安全带了
I can't get the seat belt off!
拉我下来  抓住我
Pull me down! Catch me!
我要升起来了  我要升起来了
I'm going up! I'm going up!
抓住我  抓住我
Get me! Grab me!
拉我下来  拉住我
Pull me down! Pull me!
我解不开安全带
I can't get the seat belt off!
解不开安全带
I can't get the belt off!
我被卡住了  卡住了
I'm stuck! I'm stuck!
抓紧炸弹  抓不住了
Hold the bomb! I can't hold on!
拉
Pull!
各位  我要被挤扁了
Guys, it's crushing me!
车
Car!
躲开
Move!
肖恩
Shane!
-肖恩  -我没事  我没事
- Shane! - I'm good! I'm good.
我没事
I'm good.
大黄蜂
Bumblebee!
各位
Hey, you guys!
走吧
Come on.
去个安全的地方
Go find someplace safe.
我为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.
找掩护
Get cover!
凯德
Cade!
汽车人  走大桥把炸弹带出市区
Autobots, get this bomb over the bridge and out of the city!
爸爸
Dad!
什么  快走
What? Come on.
我来吧
I got it!
我会把这个炸弹带出去
I'm getting this bomb out of here!
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
现在就剩你我了
It's you and me now!
擎天柱现在是孤军奋战了
Look, Optimus is out there all alone.
什么  你帮不了他
What? You can't help him.
我必须去  泰莎  他也为我们回来了
I have to, Tess. He came back for us.
爸  别去  求你
Dad, don't leave, please.
我会来找你的  我会的  好吗
Look, I'll find you, I'll get there, okay?
爸爸  别去  你会死掉的
Dad, no, you'll die!
和肖恩待在一起  你不会有事的
You gotta stay with Shane. You're gonna be okay.
你向我保证  照顾她一辈子
You promise me you are gonna keep her safe
直到世界末日  向我保证
rest of her life, until the end of time! Promise me!
我保证
I promise you.
你才是我最棒的创造  泰莎
You're the best thing I ever made, Tess.
永远不要忘记  从来都是你
All right, don't ever forget it, it was always you.
-我爱你  -求你别去
- I love you. - Please.
赶紧上车
Get in the car, now.
爸爸
Dad!
擎天柱
Prime!
停车
Stop the car!
-你最好听他的  -不  你给我听着
- You better listen. - No, you listen.
我绝不会抛下我父亲
I'm not leaving my dad.
好的  我们要守住这道防线
All right, we're gonna hold the line,
那就截断这座桥
then block the bridge!
你看  做人就需要有耐心
You see, it takes patience to make a man.
耐心的守望  等待
The patience to watch and wait,
静静地守护着我们
to protect all of us, quietly,
为了上帝为了祖国
for God and country,
哪怕无人认同也一样
without any recognition at all!
凯德
Cade!
外星人没有什么好坏之分  耶格
There are no good aliens! Or bad aliens, Yeager.
只有敌我之分
It's just us and them.
而你  选择了敌人那边
And you chose them.
随时奉陪
Anytime.
你宁愿牺牲自己也要救一个人类
You saved the human instead of saving yourself?
你简直是我们的耻辱
You bring shame upon us all.
她从来就不听话  从来不听
She never listens. Never.
我给你下了命令
I gave you an order!
离开这里  快
Get out of here, now!
上车  上车
Get in. Get in.
这边  喂
Hey, you! Hey!
凯德  离开这里  这是我的战斗
Cade, get out of here! This is my fight!
不  是我的
It's my fight,
而你们都得死
and you're all gonna die!
开车开车
Go! Go!
加油加油
Come on! Come on!
杀人的机器人  去死吧你
Yeah! Killer robot, my ass!
来吧
Come on.
离开  你们快点离开这里
Get away, all of you!
加油泰莎  加油泰莎  加油泰莎
Come on, Tess. Come on, Tess. Come on, Tess.
开车
Drive!
见到了我  你的末日就到了
You see my face, your life is done!
快点快点快点
Come on, come on, come on!
至死不渝
Honor to the end.
不后悔遇到我吧
You still happy we met?
永远不会
Always.
快点
Hurry!
快  我要引爆紧闭的手榴弹了
Quickly! I'm setting off lockdown's grenade!
抓紧了
Hold tight!
我们还会见面的  擎天柱
We shall meet again, Prime,
因为我回来了
for I am reborn.
这次换我照顾你的感觉也不错
Kind of nice being your hero for a change.
你一直都在照顾着我
You always were.
自始至终
All my life.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
我们回去参加毕业舞会吧
Let's go home to graduation, huh?
你没事了  孩子
You're okay, kid.
过来  你没事了  没事了
Come here, you're all right. You're all right.
我们没有家了  爸爸
We don't have a home, dad.
它被炸掉了
It blew up.
我想这事我可以帮忙
I might be able to help you with that.
勇敢的战士们
Brave warriors...
你们自由了
... you are free!
随时愿意与你并肩作战  斯派克
I'll ride with you anytime, Spike!
你想我了吗
Did you miss me?
没
No.
这颗种子属于我们的创造者
This seed belongs to our creators,
不管它们是谁
whoever they are.
捉拿我的悬赏也还在
There remains a price on my head.
如果我留下你们都会有危险
I endanger you all if I stay.
我要把它藏起来  不让人发现
I shall take it where it can never be found.
我们还会再见吗
Will we ever see you again?
凯德·耶格
Cade Yeager,
我不知道
I do not know.
但不论何时当你仰望星辰
But whenever you look to the stars,
请把其中一颗
think of one of them
当作我的灵魂
as my soul.
守护这个家  汽车人
Defend this family, autobots,
如同他们守护着你
as they have you.
守护他们
Defend
守护他们的未来
all they can be.
宇宙中有许多奥秘
There are mysteries to the universe
本无答案
we were never meant to solve.
但寻找本真和存在的意义
But who we are and why we are here
并不在其中
are not among them.
那些答案
Those answers
从来都在我们的灵魂深处
we carry inside.
这是我  擎天柱
I am Optimus Prime
对我的创造者说
and this message is to my creators:
别来找地球的麻烦
Leave planet earth alone.
因为我
'Cause I'm coming
会找你们的
for you.